<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- the line above is the "XML declaration"; it is not -->
<!-- required, but we recommend using it -->
<?xml-model href="../schemas/exercise.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../schemas/exercise.isosch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!-- the two lines above are processing instructions for finding the schema; -->
<!-- they are intended for oXygen, but other software might use them, also -->
<?xml-stylesheet title="TEI Boilerplate" type="text/xsl" href="teibp.xsl"?>
<!-- the line above is a processing instruction that asks that -->
<!-- this file be transformed by "teibp.xsl" -->
<?xml-stylesheet title="your own CSS"    type="text/css" href="../css/tiny_TEI_template.css" alternate="yes"?>
<!-- the line above is a processing instruction that asks that -->
<!-- this file be styled by "tiny_TEI_template.css" -->
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" >
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title><!-- put title here --></title>
        <author>
          <persName><!-- author's name here --></persName>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher><!-- publisher here --></publisher>
        <availability>
          <ab><!-- copyright or copyleft information here --></ab>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <!-- source information here; better yet, use a <biblStruct> instead -->
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <front>
      <div><head>THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</head>
      <ab><num type="volume">VOL. I.</num>
      Three Dollars per Annum. Single Copies 61/4 Cents.
        <placeName>NEW YORK</placeName>,<date when="1845-06-28">SATURDAY, JUNE 28, 1845.</date>
      C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.
          <num type="issue">NO. 26.</num>
      Published at 135 Nassau-St. By JOHN BISCO.</ab></div>
    </front>
    <body><div>
<lb/>
        <div>
          <head>THE ADVENTURES OF A GENTLEMAN IN SEARCH OF A DINNER. <lb/>RELATED BY HIMSELF.
            <lb/>(Continued.) </head>
          <lb/>
          <p>The Franklin Coffee House, though very far from being a Todgerses, is patronized only
            by commercial gentlemen, who either live “up town,” or lodge in their stores. They are
            early diners of course, and I found the coffee-room almost de-eerted, for it was past
            five when I entered. One or two Birmingham and Manchester agents, gentleman who deal in
            fish- hooks and spool-cotton, were finishing their dinners with brandy and water, and a
            bit of cheese and a tart. I was quite appalled at the looks of the waiter, who seemed to
            say ; “ indeed, sir, you don’t think of axing for dinner at this time o’day ?” With a
            half eagle in my pocket, I would not have cared a copper for their impertinent looks,
            but it struck me that it would be regarded as a very suspicious circumstance to ask for
            credit at that unseasonable hour, and I perceived on glancing my eye towards the bar
            that my friend, the fat proprietor was absent. My appetite had been sharpened to the
            extremest point of endurance by a peep at the larder, but I was yet able to preserve
            something like self-respect. I will not forfeit my honor, I said, if I starve for it;
            and then an idea popped into my head, which must have been striving a long while for
            entrance ; it was the most unaccountable thing in the world, that I should never once
            have thought of going in pursuit of the cab-driver to recover my half eagle. I started
            on the instant, forgetting in my hurry the cravings of my stomach, and just as I was
            turning the corner of Nassau street, I heard somebody call me by name. Looking round I
            perceived my friend Skillet, in a Rockaway waggon. <lb/></p><p>“ How are you, F.,” said
            Skillet, checking his horse. </p><lb/><p>“ Very well,” I replied, “but don’t stop me, I am half
            dead.” </p><p>“ Are you so, then jump into my waggon and_let me give you a lift.” </p><lb/><p>This was
            kind, and although I preferred not being jostled over the pavements in my condition, yet
            as I should get to the end of my journey the sooner for it, I accepted of his
            invitation. </p><lb/><p>“ Now, F.,” said Skillet, “ you have often promised to call upon Mrs.
            Skillet, but you never have done so. Come, go home with me and take a cup of tea. I live
            in Seventieth street, and I will send you home at nine.” </p><lb/><p>A cup of tea to a man in
            my situation! </p><lb/><p>“ By the way, what have you got in that basket which I saw hanging
            under your waggon ?" </p><lb/><p>“ Nothing, but a smoked salmon and some radishes;” re- plied
            Skillet. </p><lb/><p>Smoked salmon and radishes, bread and butter, cakes, pre- served fruits,
            strawberries and cream, a cup of delicious young hyson, and perhaps something else,
            flashed through my thoughts. </p><p>“ I will go upon one condition,” I said. </p><lb/><p>“ Name it,
            name it;" said Skillet. </p><lb/><p>“ That you give me some of that salmon for my supper.”</p>
            <p>“Agreed. Jump in.” </p><lb/><p>Accordingly, I did jump in—to the fire, out of the frying- pan
            in which I was suffering at the time </p><cb/><lb/><p>Skillet kept talking to me all the way about
            his business, <lb/> his importations, sales and losses ; but I could understand nothing
            that he said, my thoughts were so busy with the smoked salmon. I had no intention of
            letting this trifling supper at Skillet’s go for a dinner. No. The dinner I would have
            the next day, and so I meant to just blunt the edge of my appetite on salmon and so
            forth, and satisfy myself, with a good hearty dinner of the most recherche description,
            at three o’clock pre- cisely the next day. I could not wait until five. And then, such a
            dinner as I would eat, should be a caution to a French cook ! In the meantime a good
            meal of broiled salmon, with other little delicacies, might well pass as a substitute
            for a dinner, with a person of my moderate desires. The cottage of my friend Skillet was
            in 70th street, near the Hudson, and quite a distance from any other dwelling. He called
            it an English cottage, but for what reason I never could learn. It was a little bit of a
            Greek temple with Venetian blinds in the place of triglyphs, and two Gothic chimneys in
            the centre. I had never dined with Skillet, for I had heard that his wife was one of
            those nuisances in a man’s house, who gives his friends unequivocal intimation that she
            only tolerates them because she must. But Skillet, who ought to know what sort of a
            person he has got for a help-meet, should not make his friends partakers of his own
            misery, by inviting them to his house. It is neither generous nor humane. </p><lb/>
            <p>Skillet’s horse was a good traveller, and we reached his cottage in very good season.
            The jostling over the pavements had rather increased my appetite, and made me anxious to
            learn whether the salmon was a large one or not. </p><lb/><p>Skillet jumped out first and
            immediately exclaimed, “ F., I am ruined ! The basket is gone.” </p><lb/><p> “ Not the basket
            with the salmon, surely,” I said, “ it can’t <lb/> be possible.” </p><lb/><p>“ Yes, upon my
            soul,” said Skillet, deliberately, “ the string by which it was fastened broke, and I
            suppose some hod-carrier will eat it for his supper. However, we will give you something
            in the place of it. Mrs. Skillet has got supper on the table I dare say.” </p><lb/><p>We walked
            into the cottage and I was introduced to Mrs. Skillet. What could have induced the man
            to marry such a woman! Mrs. S. was a —-. But I will not waste words <lb/>upon such an
            icicle. An icicle ! Let me recall the simile. An icicle will melt, but nothing could
            melt such a dry stick as Mrs. Skillet. One thing I will say of her; she kept her house
            like wax-work, as the vulgar say. It was curiously clean, and glossy. The tea-table was
            spread in the hall, a rather capacious one with a straw carpet on the floor, very cool
            and pleasant. I would not, or rather I dared not trust myself to look at the table, lest
            I should be tempted to commit some impropriety. Skillet showed me his library,
            consisting almost entirely of new works and illustrated Bibles, for he was fond of light
            reading and his wife was pious ; he then took me into his garden and gave me the history
            of all his vegetables, besides telling me a long story about a grape vine which some
            people called a scuppernong, and others a golden chasselas. All this time I was in the
            greatest impatience conceivable, thinking of the supper and trying to get a scent of
            something broiling. <pb n="402"/>
            <lb/>Even after the servant had summoned us to tea, Skillet insist-ed that I should stop
            and examine his dahlias which were only a foot above ground. At last we went into the
            house and found Mrs. Skillet at the table. The prospect was dreadful, but there was
            something to hope for, a covered dish in the centre of the table might contain,
            oysters—mutton chops— warm or cold chicken—anything that was good and solid, although,
            from its size it could not contain much of anything let it be what it would. Besides the
            covered dish there was nothing upon the table but a few slices of bread, a plate of dry
            rusk, a butter plate and the tea equipage, as Skillet called it. How could a gentleman
            and a Christian set a hungry friend down to such a table. However, I do not blame
            Skillet; the fault was his wife’s. But slender as the prospect seemed, I was in a hurry
            to realize some of the promises before me. Mrs. Skillet must prolong my sufferings by
            asking a blessing. And then with a most unthankful look she asked me if I took sugar and
            cream in my tea. I took both, of course, but the cream was a thin bluish substance, that
            resembled milk and water, and she poured it out of the cream-jug in a little slender
            stream as though it were some precious essence. Skillet reached the bread and I caught
            two slices and they were gone in a moment, and then I took two more and the plate was
            empty. Mrs. S. looked amazed and called for more bread. The centre dish still remained
            covered and my eyes were fixed intently upon it, which Skillet perceived and said, “ my
            dear, what have you got here ?" he raised the cover, and, what do you think was revealed
            to my longing sight ? But you never could think. </p><lb/><p>It was a dish of red currants !</p>
            <lb/><p>I must have shown my disappointment, for Skillet himself blushed, and looking up
            said, “perhaps you would like a relish of some kind ?” </p><lb/><p>" Well, to tell the truth, I
            would,” I replied. <lb/>Mrs. Skillet said she believed there was some cold mutton in the
            pantry, and ordered Bridget to bring it. </p><lb/><p>Cold mutton! I think I never listened to
            two words which fell so pleasantly upon my hearing. Cold mutton! There must be a leg, or
            a breast, at least. I am not only fond of mutton, but I am particularly fond of it cold
            ; perhaps she will bring a pickle and mustard with it, who knows. And I think I could
            eat even a cold potatoe with a relish. These thoughts and many more flitted through my
            mind while Bridget was gone. By and by I heard her approaching, I looked up as she
            entered and there was nothing in her hand. The cat had got into the pantry and eaten the
            mutton. </p><lb/><p>“ Well, well,” said Skillet, “ I will kill that cat if I live to catch
            her.” </p><lb/><p>“ It’s of no consequence, my dear,” said his wife, “ there was but little of
            it.” </p><lb/><p>I had now no hopes of anything, and I ate two or three more slices of bread
            and butter and a rusk which only set my appetite sharper. The tea was good. I will give
            Mrs. Skil-let credit for that. As for the currants, I didn’t touch them. </p><lb/><p>Perhaps I
            am violating the rights of hospitality in thus exposing the economy of my friend's
            table, but it appears to me that it is one of those cases that require exposure. If a
            man will impose upon his friends he should be made an example of. To think of setting a
            dry rusk and a saucer of currants before me, who had eaten nothing in twenty-four hours.
            However, a dinner, and a good one too I was determined to have; no supper, nor breakfast
            would satisfy me, else I would have gone directly from Skillet’s to Florence's or
            Downing's, and gorged myself with oysters or lobsters, or something of that kind.
            Skillet perceived that I was discontented about something, although, I am not sure that
            he understood the right cave, and proposed taking me home. I was glad enough to <cb/><lb/>go,
            and as we rode into town, although the night was extremely dark I kept a sharp look-out
            for the lost basket with the salmon, determined, if we found it, to make Skillet go back
            and have some broiled for my supper, but we did not find it, and after I reached home I
            bade my friend good night in a very ill-tempered mood. </p><lb/><p>Suddenly I encountered my
            two old chums, the best fellows in the world and my very dearest friends S. and L. They
            had just arrived from Boston, and, like myself, were as hungry as a cross-cut saw. “
            Come, go with us and get some oysters,” said L. </p><lb/><p>“No,” I replied, “I am saving my
            appetite for dinner to-morrow.”</p> <lb/><p>They both laughed vociferously at my answer, and
            taking hold of my arms, said “that I should go with them.” </p><lb/><p>“Well,” said I, “ my
            friends, I will go with you, but I will eat none of your oysters. But If you are
            disposed to treat me, I will eat a piece of smoked salmon.” </p><lb/><p>“ Smoked salmon !”
            exclaimed both together ; “ have you lost your senses, F. ?” </p><lb/><p>“Almost,” I said, “but
            they have been wandering after a bit of smoked salmon.” </p><lb/><p>Here, the merry creatures
            broke into a boisterous laugh again, and the next moment I found myself in a cellar;
            where there was a crowd of people intently occupied in swallowing oysters. The place was
            .new to me, but it seemed like an old establishment, for the tables and chairs were
            ricketty, the walls were black with smoke, and the waiters were gray headed negroes ;
            the only sounds heard were the grating of the oyster knives, and the constant smack of
            the lips among the oyster eaters. There were no flaunting red curtains, no gilding, no
            salacious paintings, no ornaments of any kind about the place. It was simply an oyster
            cellar, so dark and damp that the bivalves might have fancied themselves in their native
            mud, until roused from their delusion by the prick of the oyster-knife. </p><lb/><p>“ Come,”
            said L., “ give your order,” and as he said it he winked at S., as though there was some
            secret understanding between them. </p><lb/><p>“ Bring me,” said S., “ two dozen of Shrewsburys
            in the shell, a French roll, a lemon, some butter, a plate of water-cresses, and the
            least drop in the world of Seignette with a lump of ice.” </p><lb/><p>“ Ditto for me,” said L.,
            “ and don’t forget a napkin.” </p><lb/><p>The waiter was about to disappear when I said, “ you
            forget me, my friends.” </p><lb/><p>“ O, a tooth-pick for F.,” said L., calling the waiter
            back. </p><lb/><p>“ No, not a tooth-pick, but a bit of salmon broiled,” I exclaimed, while the
            sweat began to start from every pore. </p><lb/><p>The next moment the Shrewsburys, the lemon,
            roll, butter, cresses, and so forth, were put upon the table and my two friends began to
            eat. O, it was a sight to see them suck in the oysters, while I sat with my mouth
            running like a Croton hydrant, and they not offering me an oyster. It is true that I had
            positively declined eating any, but still, as my salmon had not been brought, they might
            have said, “ F., won’t you take an oyster !” I knew that I should have been welcome, but
            I had a strange delicacy of feeling about taking one without being invited. </p><lb/><p>In a
            very short time the Shrewsburys had disappeared and nothing but the shells remained. My
            friends smacked their lips with infinite satisfaction, and directly the old white-headed
            negro re-appeared. </p><lb/><p>“ Come,” said S., “ give your order,” and he winked again at L."</p>
            <lb/><p>“ Let me see,” said L., “ shall we have the fried or broiled first?" </p><pb n="403"/>
            <lb/><p>“ The broiled, the broiled, by all means,” said S. </p><lb/><p>“ Salmon, of course;" said
            I. </p><lb/><p>“No, oysters;” said L. “ Waiter, bring us two dozen of broiled oysters, let them
            be done to a turn, well buttered but not peppered, more French rolls, a head of fresh
            lettuce, and a small bottle of chateau Margaux.” </p><lb/><p>“ Ditto for me,” said S." </p><lb/>
            <p>But, my friends,” said I, “ you forget the salmon.”</p> <lb/><ab>[To be continued.]</ab></div>
        <div><lb/><head>BRITISH CRITICISMS ON AMERICAN ART. </head><lb/><p>The late London papers contain several
          notices of American works of Art at present in that city. Among them we find the following
          on a portrait by Inman, in the Exhibition of the Royal Academy, which we have extracted
          from the Art-Union. </p><lb/><quote type="block">“<title>Portrait of Mrs. G. Putnam</title>. H. Inman. This work is hung so high
          that it is difficult to distinguish its nicer qualities. The style is retiring, and the
          general color managed with much delicacy. Mr. Inman is the leading portrait painter of
          America, and merits the high fame he has recently obtained in his own country. He has
          recently visited England, where he has painted portraits of Chalmers, Wordsworth, and
          other ‘great men.’ These we have seen, and consider among the best works of modem art.
          There are, indeed, few of our own artists who could surpass them. The picture here
          exhibited may be good or may be bad; the hangers have left the matter at all events a
          question,” </quote><lb/><p>Mr. Doughty has a landscape in the exhibition of the Royal Academy, which,
          like Mr. Inman’s picture, is also hung out of sight. It is thus noticed in the Art-Union:</p>
          <lb/><quote type="block">“ We are deprived of the power to inspect this picture from its being hung so high.
          All we can say is that the view seems to have been selected with judgment, and made the
          most of, as to general effect; and if it be as good as, or better than, productions of his
          pencil with which we are acquainted, it is a picture which ought, in common justice, to
          have been placed more on a level with the eye.” </quote><lb/><p>We have seen no notices of either of
          the other American pictures in the Exhibition. Probably they were hung so that they could
          not be seen at all. The Art-Union notices a picture by Howard, R. A., in the following
          terms: “ Placed as this production is, upon the line, and in one of the most prominent
          situations in the best room, we feel called upon to speak of the work in terms of decided
          condemnation. Men who, like the contributors from Germany, Belgium and America, have been
          subjected to gross indignities by the British Royal Academy, will naturally institute
          comparisons between their degraded ‘ offerings’ and such lamentable exposing as this.”</p>
          <lb/><p>The “ Greek Slave” by Powers, has been very generally praised by the London journals,
          and one of his female busts is pronounced by Mr. Titmarsh, in Frazer’s Magazine, to be the
          best one in the exhibition. The Art-Union says of the statue : “ In a few words, we pay
          the artist the highest compliment that can be offered : it is insufficient to say that the
          work reminds us of the antique,—it competes successfully with the best remnants of Greek
          Art.” The criticism of the Athenaeum is more particular, but quite as flattering ; it is
          the best that we have seen, and therefore we copy it, as it will give a very good idea of
          the work: </p><lb/><quote type="block"><p>“ We have seen a statue, by an American artist, Mr. Hiram Powers, which its
          purchaser, Mr. Grant, has brought over from Florence; and, with the zeal of a generous
          patron, has sent for exhibition to the rooms of Mr. Graves, the print-seller in Pall
          Mall,—determined, as he declares, to make the public sharers in his admiration of the
          sculptor. Our readers may remember that Mrs. Trollope, in her ‘ Visit to Italy,’ gave some
          account of this artist,—whom she had fallen in with at Cincin-natti, a mere modeller of
          wax figures, and afterwards at Florence, in the flush of his ripened talent and an Italian
          fame. The work in question has in fact attracted a great deal of no- <cb/><lb break="no"/>tice
          ; and during the short period of its exhibition, Mr. Grant <lb/>has, we understand, had
          several offers for its -purchase—the <lb/>Duke of Southerland and the Marquis of
          Northampton having been named to us as among the parties who have been desirous to possess
          themselves of it. Its present proprietor, however, will dispose of it only to a public
          institution. With the National Gallery or the British Museum he is willing to treat, for
          the honor of the artist; but if the work is to be confined to a private gallery, he
          chooses that gallery to be his own. His determination has, however, done better for the
          sculptor than any transfer of the statue in question ; it being understood that Mr. Grant,
          who is about to return to Florence, takes with him several commissions for the young
          American. The figure in question is certainly a very remarkable work,—and might be thought
          still more so as the work of an American, were it not remembered that the sculptor has
          been for ten or a dozen years past resident in Florence, where his genius has fed on the
          Greek inspiration, and outlived, it may be supposed, the chastening apprehension of the
          prudes at home. </p><lb/><p>“ The work represents a Greek Captive; and professes to embody a
          historical fact—the exposure of female slaves for sale in a Turkish bazaar, during one of
          the early Greek revolutions. The figure is entirely naked; and the nudity, in this case,
          is of a peculiarly daring character, exactly in as far as it is historical and not
          spontaneous—because, instead of being, like some of the finest figures of the same class,
          abstractions of loveliness, in which the sense of nakedness is subdued by the suggestion
          of privacy and the sentiment of utter unconsciousness,—the rich proportions are, in this
          instance, presented with a direct view to their voluptuous character and intention, and
          make the same appeal to the critic’s judgment of merely physical form, which they are
          supposed to be at the moment making in the sensualist’s market. There is no escaping from
          this aspect of the work; and the very sentiment of shame and disgust which mingles with
          the sorrow on the sweet face, only enforces that impression,—being a further and most
          expressive reference to the subject. It is a great mistake on the artist’s part to have
          placed his figure in such a predicament—to have chosen a story like this as the vehicle
          for an exhibition of its beauties ; and in this view of it, it is an additional misfortune
          that the sculptor’s type of female form is a somewhat massive one—the mortal proportions
          submitted to no process of refining or idealizing.— The story, however, received as
          legitimate, is powerfully told. The character and sentiment of the situation are conveyed
          with a masterly hand. Nothing need surpass the ease and freedom of attitude and movement,
          or the simplicity of manner by which they are attained. The composition and modelling are
          of first rate excellence; the former so skilfully arranged, that no view of the figure can
          be taken which does not bring into combination many of the fine effects of the latter.
          There are parts of the execution, especially in the back of the figure, full of fine lines
          and beautiful hints—which exhibit a hand of high power. When we speak of the massive
          character of the beauty of this work, perhaps we should qualify the expression by some
          explanation of our meaning. If this figure be tested by some of the finest antiques, or by
          a work like Baily’s ‘ Nymph,’ now in the Academy, it should be born in mind that, in each
          of those, there is a selection of features and proportions —real and human in themselves,
          but combined and assorted, after the sculptor’s sense of beauty, into a shape which takes
          thus the character of the ideal. But this is a real woman—living and acting and
          suffering—flesh in its earthly proportions—a Greek slave—a figure which, in sentiment and
          form, may stand for the ‘ Ionian Myrrha;’ and it is modelled with a careful study and
          anatomical observance which some of our sculptors might do well to consult. The figure is
          wrought out of a beautiful block of Serravezza marble ; and there are some of its muscular
          accidents which imitate the flesh in a manner quite marvellous for such a substance. The
          modem Greek costume is displayed on a column, on which the right hand of the Captive rests
          ; and the Cross is there, to express her religion and country. The chains on the wrist are
          not historical, but used as accessories, and have a very clever application in the
          composition. We know not if the Transatlantic mind be sufficiently expanded out of its
          conventional proprieties, since Mrs. Trollope’s day, to receive a latitudinarian artist
          like Mr. Powers with the honors of ‘ a prophet in his own country ;’—but certain it is,
          that, by his means, the Americans may boast of a sculptor in Europe.” </p></quote><lb/><p>Laughing
          Gas.—The Tribune has employed Professor Bacon to administer doses of this exhilirating
          substance to its readers. Two doses have already been given, and a third promised </p><pb
            n="404"/></div>
<lb/>
        <div type="section"><head>CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN A MOTHER AND GOVERNESS. </head><lb/><div><head>My Dear Friend :</head><p>—I am quite easy
          about my children, as they are left in your care, and my mind, free from anxiety, is open
          to any passing enjoyment which the state of my health allows me to partake. I took a drive
          of a few miles yesterday with my brother, whose conversation with all his variety of
          entertaining knowledge, made it very pleasant. I told him I intended, on my return, to
          furnish my garden with native plants, the shrubs as well as the small flowers, and among
          the rest, the cornet, but he says, though variety is good, the virburnam is more
          beautiful. He remarked also, that the species of sumach, that hears green flowers is the
          finest; but as the red flowers are prettier, he should like to have both. I took a walk by
          the brook, that runs through his farm, while he visited a patient who lives near. When he
          joined me, he said, his patient had consulted, formerly, an inefficient practitioner,
          whose doses were always too small. My brother says, when you hit the nail upon the head
          you should strike hard enough to drive it in. This man’s practice is, as if I should put a
          few grains of belladonna into this stream, and then tell my patients to come drink the
          water and be cured. I was much pleased with my ramble ; the cardinal, monkey flower, and
          snakehead, were blooming by the brook, with a few lingering specimens of the elegant
          hybrid loose-strife. I had a glance at a distance of a marmot, eating the grass, and
          walking through the wood, where grew the splendid yellow gerardin ; I saw the entrance to
          his subterraneous abode, in which he is as safe and secure as a nobleman in his castle. If
          the brute creation are not, as the Egyptians thought, proper objects of worship, watching
          their ways may well lead the thoughts to the Divinity. My brother visited another patient,
          who had not taken his medicines, and with just resentment he was going to abandon him, but
          I dissuaded him, as I thought if he did, it would distress the patient’s mother. My
          brother is unfortunate in having a very sickly wife, who is prohibited by ill health, from
          the activity, that would make her either happy in herself, or useful to others. I pity her
          for this, and also for the censures, to which she is subjected by not mixing with the
          world. Public opinion subjects her to the same ordeal the witches were liable to in old
          times, for she can prove herself in no way unequal to the common engagements of life, but
          by dying. She sometimes thinks that my brother had better followed in his choice the ideas
          of Aikin and Combe, but he does not repent of it, as he loves his wife. She is
          uncomfortable, notwithstanding her husband’s love, for she is stretched on Procrustes’
          bed, and the neighbors (neighbors) remark, “ she would not be sick, if she did not think
          she was, and one never sees the inside of her house.” My brother has educated in part his
          wife’s nephew, whose mother is a widow, and who, like himself, takes greatly to natural
          history, botany especially. This youth’s mother, an energetic woman, is justly anxious,
          that her son, above everything should learn to get a living, and she tells him that while
          he is looking at the lining of the nests of birds, he will not learn to feather his own
          nest, and when inquiring so much, what the birds eat for breakfast, he will perhaps come
          short of a provision for his own dinner. I shall stay here sometime longer, as my health
          is manifestly improving under my brother’s care. </p><ab>Yours, <lb/>E------- M--------. </ab><lb/><p>P.
          S. Tell Ruth next time she broils a chicken, to put a plate on it in which a flat-iron is
          to be set, to press it down ; something I saw done here with great advantage. </p></div><lb/><div><head>Dear
          Mrs. M--------,</head> <p>Do not trust me too much. I will not <lb/>thank you for your expressions
          of confidence, it would be so base in me not to mean to do all I can. I am sensible I can
          <lb/><cb/> only be a slender auxiliary to a mother. I shall often be stupid, I fear sometimes
          sleep at my post. We too are collecting flowers, insects also interest the children ;
          other pursuits are somewhat overlooked just now, for when the tide drives to a good port I
          like to take advantage of it. You can imagine how it seems here, such a spreading of
          petals, creeping, flut- tering, and leaping all around. Something new is discovered, and
          flown up to, and made a prize of in every walk. The young folks are for doing little else
          at present but gather the golden sands, of the temporary stream that is washing them down.
          All our botanical and entomological books are drawn from their winter repose, and heaped
          up on the table. When they go back to the shelves, we shall wake to other things. Much
          delight was expressed with your plan of bringing home for loving companions, the beautiful
          ornaments of the woods. Your fresh enthusiasm reminds me of the time when we were
          <lb/>turning about to come home from----------Swamp, loaded with <lb/>the great laurel and
          you said, “ don’t you think we are as bad as Lord Elgin, when he robbed Athens of its
          marbles.” The thing will not be quite what the children anticipate, though a very good
          measure. They are not so well aware as I, that the forest-flower in the garden is shorn of
          its natural glories, the shady place, the sudden appearance, the lovely carpet of quiet
          brown leaves or grass, on which it sets its delicate foot, the tripping stream, the
          picturesque gray rock, the majestic tree it smiles upon. The children have begun to count
          up the viburnums among the shrubs. You must have, James says, every species. It is
          pleasant to see the various members of a genus side by side. I love much to contemplate
          the genus <lb/>M------together. James, you know, wants nothing less than <lb/>a cornucopia
          in his hand all the time. The firm Alfred frowns, and says, “ get one first, and see if we
          can make it live.” He and Mary have been looking very assiduously for a trientales gone to
          seed. They are quite excited about it, it had so seldom been seen ; even Linnaeus, of whom
          the flower was a darling, failed. Smith decribes it, as in harmony with its general
          beauty, its delicate petals or petal, its slender stems stamens like hairs, its circle of
          pointed-filing leaves corresponding with its circle of pointed petals, leaves so thin and
          expanded that if endowed with locomotion, it would naturally float on the air. As Smith’s
          description may not be at hand, and you might be induced to join in the search for the
          rarity, I will copy it. “The spreading valves of the capsule are highly polished
          internally, and the seeds are enveloped in a most elegant white net-work.” </p><lb/><p>This
          morning, Edith, reading of the lilies of Palestine, that surpassed the magnificence of
          Solomon, wished to know what flower was meant. I looked in Sprengel’s Flora Biblica, and,
          to my surprise, did not find it. None in the list can, I think, have been so often the
          subject of inquiry. These wondrous lines and hues of beauty, lavished on so transient a
          splendor, were never viewed so holily by other eyes. It shames those who, giving thanks
          for the “ fruitful season,” are blind to the divine gift of flowers. </p><lb/><p>Did you ever
          observe Homer's love of flowers ? Mercury, sent on a message to Calypso, is charmed with
          the flowers he finds on her island—the violet and (Sprengel says) the celery. </p><lb/><p>“
          Herme’s, Heaven's messenger, admiring stood." </p><lb/><p>The Greeks looked upon the celery,
          (called parsley by our translators,) I find, as a plant of dignity. It was sacred to the
          infernal gods, and crowned the victor in the Isthmian games. <lb/>I am indebted for this
          to Sprengel’s Flora Homerica. </p><lb/><p>James has become quite a nice observer. He entertains
          uncle and mother too, and wonders they overlooked the green flowers that in all the
          sumachs precede the berries, whether crimson-haired or green. I should not repeat this
          except to the meet ingenuous of mothers. </p><pb n="405"/>
          <lb/><p>The young naturalist must become a clergyman, have a country parish, and produce for
          us here such charming epistles as we owe to White of Selborne. Do you remember how we
          longed for this book when we first met with Miss Edgeworth’s mention of it, and how I at
          last sent to England for it? (When shall I be so much interested again about any similar
          innocent little thing ?) The brute, or the “ mute” creation have had their early day
          here—savage reverence; the naturalists and poets are crowding along now, to look to its
          flowers. The American poets have certainly celebrated them more warmly and graphically
          than any other poets. Who, in England, have ever worshipped Flora like Bryant, Street, and
          Emerson ? </p><lb/><p>If I had more time, I would write more. You may suppose all are well, and,
            still better, active.</p> <ab>N----- S-----. </ab></div><lb/><div><head>Mrs. M----- to Mrs. S----. </head><lb/><p>Dear Mrs. : In
          this compelled absence from my children, I can never enough congratulate myself upon
          having such a substitute as you. I think their iron axe being lost in the pool, they have
          found a golden one. </p><lb/><p>My young naturalist, as you call him, is still pursuing plants in
          the fields and woods. He says he has analyzed all within five miles; but he must not
          believe this fully. He came home the other day, and showed a handfull of asters to my
          brother, who remarked, that Cowley called all flowers stars; and the other day, when he
          brought home grass of Parnassus, that he thought that must be what Pegassus lived on. I
          overheard the chambermaid say to the cook the other day, “ Mr. Henry has got something he
          calls asters, but he does not speak it right— he means oysters; but they are not so nice
          as Chaney ones.’’ “ That angelico that he got,” said she, “ is a beautiful airb.” The cook
          wonders at Mr. Henry for keeping caterpillars; they are, she says, only fit to tread on;
          and she despises butterflies, both as being common and because they spring from something
          so mean as a caterpillar—having, you see, a great regard for honorable descent. I enclose
          you a little bagatelle of Henry. </p></div><lb/><div><head>The Cherrybird to Sylvanus Dewberry, Esq.</head> <lb/><p>Sir :
          As I do not belong to a literary race, you may be surprised to receive a letter from me ;
          but I was reminded, by the sealing-wax on my wings, to make this beginning of an
          epistolary correspondence. As I am a near relation to the Waxen Chatterer of England, it
          is not to be wondered at that I should have some sociability. Travellers are naturally
          communicative, and I am a great one—having come to visit you from the flowery plains of
          Mexico; making a short sojourn, as I passed along, in the southern and middle States.</p>
          <lb/><p>But I like temperate climates, where grow cherries and mulberries; for those juicy
          fruits are my favorite food. On the fourth of July, (which the cherries make a day of
          jubilee to me,) I hear a great deal said of the rights of men, and I wish to put in a word
          of appeal, in behalf of the claims of cherry-birds. Gratitude is said to be a just debt;
          and why should you not then be willing to reward the services, and celebrate the merits,
          of the cherry-birds ? Birds, as well as men, love glory and good fare. America
          commemorates, by a granite monument, the heroes of the Revolution. England gave Blenheim
          to the illustrious Duke of Marlborough; and the splendors of Apsley-House attest the
          nation’s gratitude to the conqueror of Waterloo. But though my brethren and I have spent
          days in devouring the pernicious canker-worm, small thanks do we get from you and other
          owners of orchards. You set a boy of straw to guard your cherry-trees, (which though,
          after we got acquainted with him, we did not mind;) it is conclusive evidence you did not
          make us welcome to your cherries. Yours, you call them; but we think there is great reason
          to conclude <cb/><lb/>they were designed for us—there is so great a correspondence and
          adaptation between our wings and the place where they grow. But lately I saw a boy
          climbing a cherry-tree, and, venturing upon too slender a limb, (which, however, would
          have supported many cherry-birds,) down he came to the ground; and, as he went limping
          along, I suppose he has learned not again to attempt an enterprise, for which wings, a
          light body, and hollow bones, would alone qualify him. When you could not, with your
          stuffed boy, frighten us away, your son comes against us with a gun, so as to leave us no
          alternative but to die, either by shot or hunger. You are so blundering, you come to
          attack us with a blunderbuss, and cannot distinguish your friends from enemies ; but on
          the faith of a bird, if you grudge us our reward in cherries and mulberries, we will let
          the canker-worm, in future, destroy, without let or molestation, your apple-trees and
          elms. </p><lb/><p>Besides, I saw the laborers, under your directions, with a sickle, doing what
          you call cutting up bushes, but I call it destroying the orchard of the birds. From your
          avarice, you cannot spare a small piece of land for the pinipee, holly, cornel, and
          myrtle-berry. </p><lb/><p>You take our lives when you do take that whereon we live. At
          thanksgiving you will eat, with relish, the nice pie made of apples that the cherry-bird
          has saved, without remembering his services. Before that time, the cold weather will have
          driven us to the flowery plains of Mexico. There, what with insects and fruits, I can get
          my living, (which I learned in Yankee-land,) though debarred from my favorite food—the
          juicy fruits of the North. I wonder your heart is not softened towards us by our rare
          beauty, (your race loves beauty,) our silken, fawn-colored plumage, brilliant eye, and
          elegant crest. But, exhausted with such an unusual exertion, I must draw to a con- <lb
            break="no"/> clusion. Shocked with your inhospitable reception, we will <lb/> leave you.
          Cherry and cedar-trees grow in other places; and, if it is our lot to find other States
          and countries as churlish, mean, and grudging as you are, we can lay down in death upon
          our mother earth. </p><lb/><ab>The Cherry-bird, alias the Cedar-bird. </ab><lb/><p>So much for our
          kind-hearted naturalist.</p></div></div>
      <lb/><div><head>DESULTORY THOUQHTS.
        <lb/>BY A SCRIBBLER.
        <lb/>'Opu  kav oreyavololv Onws npenel ta vevka podois kpiva nvaxevra
        <lb/>______ Anacreon.
        <lb/>No. I.</head>
<p>        <lb/>I like sometimes to take up my pen and let it run on at random, without 
  the trouble of confining it to any one object, or definite end. To be sure, there 
  is the old difference between easy writing and easy reading, which is apt, on such 
  occasions, to stare one uncomfortably in the face ; but readers not unfrequently
  happen to be in the same mood, and are glad to escape from the weight of fixing 
  the intellect on an elaborate essay, content to let the languid attention follow 
  the artist’s pen, without much caring about the connexion or individuality of the
  subjects. To these easy-minded persons I address myself now ; certain, at least, 
  that if my easy writings prove not to be easy reading, it will soon cease to be 
  any species of reading whatsoever. Every literary man must find, in the course of
  his studies, that detached thoughts and reflections arise and are stored up, which
  are never called for in the train of his regular pursuits, and such desultory 
  scribbling as this serves to brighten them up and leads him to recal old times
  and associations, the memory of which is indeed sweet
</p><cb/>        <pb  n="406"/>
        <lg> <l>Eheu fugaces, Posthume, Posthume,</l>
        <l>Labuntur anni'</l></lg>
<p> <lb/>I have been looking to-day over some of my favorites among the lesser stars of the Minor Greek Poets, for whom I feel an especial reverence, as having afforded me many a delightful hour. I regret much to see, despite other evidences of the advancement and improvement of our country, how little the old masters of the heart are cultivated and appreciated among us. One of the most favored of us, on leaving his studies, has, perchance, been driven through three books of Homer, a tragedy of Euiripides, and an ode or two of Pindar. Thoroughly disgusted with the whole, from alpha to omega, he casts them aside with all haste, and ever afterwards thinks of them but as the forced tasks of his boyhood. This is not as it should be. Leaving out of consideration the acknowledged great ones of antiquity, over whom every college youth trips and stumbles, there is a fund of the truest genius among the minor poets of Greece alone almost sufficient to repay the time and labor of learning the language ; and yet they are scarcely known in this country, even by name. Who, that is acquainted with the treasures that lie concealed in the Greek Anthology, the charming creations of Philip of Thessalonica, Macedonius the Consul, Julian the Egyptian, Posidippus, Antipater of Sidonia, Antiphilus, Meleager, Agathias the Scholiast, Argantarius, and a host of others even less known, or the few and melancholy fragments that remain to us of Simonides, Mimnermua of Colophon,* Bacchy-lides, the epigrams of Callimachus, and others, would be content to part with the key unlocking the casket ? True, there have been various translations given to the world. Merivale is sometimes happy in catching the spirit of the original, and Bland is not without skill as an interpreter. Elton’s “ Specimens of the Classic Poets” contains many gems, though not well set; William Hay, in Blackwood’s Magazine for 1834 and ’35, has translated a large part of the Anthology without taste, judgment or skill, and Christopher North, some ten years since, had a most excellent series of papers in his own free and easy, prose-run-mad style, In which he embalmed not a few precious relics of antiquity. But all this is no recompense for the original, as it is almost impossible to catch the mingled grace and beauty of spirit and diction which renders these valued fragments so inimitable.
</p> <lb/><p>Mimnermus of Colophon has always been an especial favorite with me, though there are but two or three disjecta membra remaining to show us what his productions originally were. His seems to have been a lyre of mournful sweetness, and the few lines which we possess are filled with laments for the shortness of youth and the miseries of age. Ex pede Herculem, I venture on a version of one of his prettiest</p>
        <lb/><lg><head>Tίς όέ βίός, γί όέ γερπνόν. κ. τ. λ.</head>
        <l>Say, what is life, or where its charm,</l>
        <l>Fair Venus, when thy power hath fled ?</l>
        <l>Oh, when my breast thou can'st not warm,</l>
        <l>May I rest coldly with the dead!</l>
        <l>Yes, when I lose the hopes of love.</l>
        <l>The secret kiss, the stol'n delights,</l>
        <l>Which in our youthful hours we prove </l>
          <l>Through days of bliss and dreamy nights.</l>
        <l>But, ah ! these blossoms of our spring.</l>
          <l>To every youth and maiden dear,</l>
        <l>Bloom only for the withering,</l>
          <l>And he who mars our pleasures here.</l></lg>
        <lb/>--------------
        <lb break="no"/><p>*By the way, I lately saw in the Southern Literary Messenger,
        <lb/>a translation of what purported to be a newly discovered epitha-
        <lb break="no"/>lamium attributed to Mimnermus. It has been copied through
        <lb/>pardions newspapers, and I should much like to see the original.--
        <lb break="no"/>Could you, Mr. Editor, manage to lay hold of the translator, and
        <lb/>obtain from him the original, together with the proof of the iden-tity?</p><cb/>
        <lb/><lg><l>Unsparing Age, with ruthless finger,</l>
        <l>Destroys each beauty where the eye </l>
          <l>Of love was wont entranced to linger,</l>
        <l>Till bliss seemed almost agony.</l>
        <l>He fills the soul with every care,</l>
        <l>He dulls the senses to the light,—</l>
        <l>Unblessed, unhonored by the fair,</l>
        <l>At last his victim sinks to night!</l></lg>
        <lb/><p>Mimnermus himself avoided these evils as long as possible, for in his old age he loved the fair Nanne, but whether the scorn-ful damsel slighted him, and made him give utterance to that complaint in the last stanza,
        <lb/><l>JXV it jii* Jraifi*, dripacroi Si yvvatgiv.</l>
        <lb/>it would now be hard to tell.</p>
  <lb/><p>But the Anthology is my favorite store-house. Long after I became acquainted with its redundant beauties, I could scarce-ly meet its name, or that of any of its principal contributors, without expressing, though of course in a minor degree, the sensation mentioned by Mimnermus on seeing a beautiful maiden—
  <lb/><lg><l>ανγίκ 'έμοί κατά μέν χροιήν ρέεί άσπεγος ίόρώς, </l>
    <l>πγοιοΰμαι δ'έσωρών άνφος όμιλικίης</l></lg>
  <lb/>and who is there that has not felt the same with his own peculiar authors ? It would scarcely be worth while here to “ hold a farthing candle to the sun,” by pretending to enter on the praise of this exquisite collection, but I will mention one advantage which it possesses in always suiting a man of variable humor. Whatever mood he may be in, here will he find something to accord with it, from the light amatory strains of Rufinua or Strata, to the tender melancholy of Meleager, or the stately yet simple sorrows of Simonides. And these productions are not to be read, stans pede in uno; they will seem to have esoteric beauties which are to be discovered only by study, and every time that we renew our acquaintance with them, they seem to have acquired fresh charms.</p>
  <lb/><p>Of the amatory writers in the Anthology, Agathias the Scholiast, and Paul the Silentiary are among the most prolific. They were friends, the latter holding an office about the court of one of the Greek emperors, and compiled what is considered as the third Anthology, adding thereto much of their own.— Though the age in which they wrote, (the fifth century) was not the most favorable to purity of style, yet their productions are singularly good. Too many of them, however, are stained with the indelicacy which is almost universal among the old writers. Here is a pretty little thing by Agathias, in one of his best moods, on
        <lb/><lg><head>WOMAN'S LOVE.
          <lb/>'Ηίφέοίς ούκ ίστι. κ. τ. λ.</head>
        <l>O Youths ! what are the names ye feel.</l>
        <l>To those that waste the virgin’s heart,</l>
        <l>So slow those burning wounds to heal,</l>
        <l>So quick to catch Love’s wandering dart</l>
        <l>Ye have companions who can share</l> 
        <l>The secret grief, and soothe it well;</l>
        <l>And ye have sports to banish care,</l>
        <l>And lofty aims to break love's spell.</l>
        <l>But we must shroud the burning thought </l>
        <l>In darkness. We must shun the day,</l>
        <l>And let the soul, thus backward brought,</l>
        <l>In silence pine itself away!</l></lg></p>
    <lb/><p>In the fifth book,* is preserved a little fragment, of which I have often desired the conclusion. The honor of its authorship is disputed by Posidippus and Asclepias.</p>
    <lb/><p>* Of the Leipsig Edition.</p>
        <pb n="407"/>
        <lb/><lg><head>Αύγοί γήν άπαλήν, κ.τ. λ. </head>
        <lb/><l>The Loves were one day leaving</l> <l>Their mother's golden room,</l>
          <lb/><l>When they spied the fair Erinnion</l> <l>In youthful beauty’s bloom.</l>
        <lb/><l>Of purest marble chiselled</l> <l>Appeared the lovely maiden,</l>
        <lb/><l>From raven hair to rosy feet</l>,
        <lb/><l>With virgin graces laden.</l>
        <lb/><l>Then each his purple bowstring </l><l>To the head with vigor drew,</l>
        <lb/><l>And at her yet unwounded breast</l> <l>Their arrows swiftly flew.</l></lg>
<p>        <lb/>Whether this was left in its present unfinished state by the poet, or whether the envious tooth of time has eaten out the conclusion, it were hard to tell; and all that remains for us is to exercise the imagination on the subsequent adventures of the fair Erinnion, so slightly yet so gracefully described. Did she end by becoming the poet’s bride, or was she doomed to wear the willow, and sleep with the early primroses, or was her “ yet unwounded breast” filled with the image of some faithless deceiver ? These are questions more easily asked than answered.</p>        
    <lb/><p>Refinus is a pleasant fellow, one of the most volatile and agreeable of the amatory bards in the Anthology. I should not like to count up the number of his pretty lady-loves, to each whom he swears the firmest attachment in tum. Many of his
        <lb/>epigrams are inserted in the fifth book, and in Strata’s
        <lb/>Mox if a
        <lb/>Uatouce.
        <lb/>I give a rough version of one most originally in-
        <lb break="no"/>elegant.</p>
        <lb/><lg><head>Eνρáπς γό ψίλημα, κ. τ. λ. </head>
        <l>Ye Gods! Europe's kiss is sweet,</l>
        <l>If her lips but give the gentlest touch </l>
          <l>To mine, whene’er they strive to meet.</l>
        <l>And drink of joys, alas! too much!</l>
        <l>And even when she doth but raise</l> <l>Her lip, in challenge of a kiss,</l>
        <l>My soul within me scarcely stays,</l>
        <l>Fluttering to reach that scene of bliss !</l></lg>
<p>        <lb/>In the last thought of these lines, one can trace some resemblance to Voiture’s beautiful little epigram of “ The Kiss.” Such images are, however, very common among the Greek Epigrammatists, and the Frenchman may hare borrowed from some one else.
</p>        <lb/><lg><l>Mon ame sur ma levre etait lors toute entiere </l>
  <l>Pour savourer le miel qui sur la votre etail;</l>
        <l>Mais, en me retirant, elle rests derriere,</l>
        <l>Tant de ce doux plaisir l'amorce 1’arretoit.</l></lg>
        <lb/><p>This has been translated very often, yet I feel inclined to try my hand at it:</p>
        <lg><l>When to thy lips I wildly clung,</l>
        <l>To mine my very soul upsprung,</l>
        <l>To taste the bliss that breathed from thee.</l>
        <l>But when that long-drawn kiss was o’er.</l>
        <l>It staid with thee, to leave no more</l> <l>The sweets that round thee ever be !</l></lg>
<p>        <lb/>But I am transgressing all due bounds, having already scribbled much more than was in my intention when I took up the pen, and I break off, feeling that I have shown some of my favorites in their least auspicious moods,—that of love. Perhaps some of my readers may feel surprised at this, but Grecian love was a very different thing from what we now understand by that name. At some future time, I may take up this prolific theme.</p>        
    <lb/><ab>H. C. L</ab>
        <lb/><ab>Philadelphia, May, 1845.</ab></div><cb/>
<lb/><div><head>DREAM-LAND.
</head>
<lg><l>By a route obscure and lonely,</l>
<l>Haunted by ill angels only,</l>
<l>Where an Eidelon, named Night,</l>
<l>On a black throne reigns upright,</l>
<l>I have reached these lands but newly</l> <l>From an ultimate dim Thule—
</l><l>From a wild weird clime, that lieth, sublime, </l><l>Out of SPACE—out of TIME.
</l><l>Bottomless vales and boundless floods. </l>
  <l>And chasms, and caves, and Titan woods, </l>
  <l>With forms that no man can discover </l>
  <l>For the dews that drip all over; </l>
  <l>Fountains toppling evermore</l> 
<l>Into seas without a shore;</l>
<l>Seas that restlessly aspire,</l>
<l>Surging, unto skies of fire ;
</l><l>Lakes that endlessly outspread</l> 
  <l>Their lone waters, lone and dead,— </l>
  <l>Their still waters, still and chilly </l>
  <l>With the snows of the lolling lily,
</l><l>By the lakes that thus outspread</l> 
  <l>Their lone waters, lone and dead,— </l>
  <l>Their sad waters, sad and chilly </l>
  <l>With the snows of the lolling lily,—
</l><l>By the mountain—near the river </l>
  <l>Murmuring lowly, murmuring ever,—
</l><l>By the grey woods,—by the swamp</l> <l>Where the toad and the newt encamp,
</l><l>By the dismal tarns and pools </l><l>Where dwell the Ghouls,—
</l><l>By each spot the most unholy—
</l><l>In each nook most melancholy,—
</l><l>There the traveler meets aghast</l> <l>Sheeted Memories of the Past— </l>
  <l>Shrouded forms that start and sigh </l><l>As they pass the wanderer by— 
  </l><l>White-robed forms of friends long given. </l>
  <l>In agony, to the worms, and Heaven.</l>
<l>For the heart whose woes are legion</l>
  <l> ’Tis a peaceful, soothing region—</l>
<l>For the spirit that walks in shadow</l>
  <l> 'Tis—oh ’tis an Eldorado!</l>
<l>But the traveller, traveling through it.</l> <l>May not—dare not openly view it;</l>
<l>Never its mysteries are exposed </l><l>To the weak human eye enclosed ;</l>
<l>So wills the king, who hath forbid </l><l>The uplifting of the fringed lid;]
</l><l>And thus the sad Soul that here passes</l> 
  <l>Beholds it but through darkened glasses.</l>
<l>By a route obscure and lonely,
</l><l>Haunted by ill angels only,
</l><l>Where an Eidolon, named Night,</l>
<l>On a black throne reigns upright,
</l><l>I have wandered home but newly </l>
  <l>From this ultimate dim Thule.</l></lg></div>
<lb/><div><head>“Time WORKS Wonders,”</head> <p>and we know of nothing that he has done in the way of
      “ work” more wonderful than making the theatrical public willing 
      to sit out the representation of Douglas Jerrold’s last comedy. There 
      is a certain cant of philanthropy about it which might insure it 
      popularity at the Hay Market, but we cannot account for its favorable 
      reception on this side of the water, on any other grounds than its being 
      the production of a Cockney. We have a great liking for Douglas Jerrold,
      but we do not like everything that he publishes.</p></div>
<pb  n="408"/>
<lb/>
<div type="section">REVIEWS.
<lb/><div><head><title>The Aesthetic Letters, Essays, and the Philosophical Letters op Schiller</title>: Translated, with an Introduction, by J.
<lb/>Weiss. Boston, Charles C. Little, and James Brown; 1845, pp.
<lb/>33 and 379.</head>
<lb/><p>Among the many flattering titles which the American people has, at 
  due intervals, seen fit to bestow upon itself, that of a j “ reading 
  people” is, perhaps, the one which has been most insisted upon and most 
  tenaciously clung to. From certain unsightly pieces of rottenness in our 
  social fabric, our claim to be the “ freest and most enlightened nation on
  the face of the earth,"” though rigorously asserted by fourth of July orators,
  and swallowed unsuspiciously by fourth of July audiences, has come to be 
  generally doubted by the thoughtful; in spite of, now and then, a Philadelphia 
  symphony or opera, which are, | indeed, reservoirs of noise vast enough, 
  if conveyed by proper ttreporiducts, to supply all the musical composers 
  of the world, we are hardly yet on a level with Germany in taste or enthu- J siasm 
  for music; our poetry is said to be conveyed, in surrep- | titious phialsfull, 
  from the English Helicon; in painting and sculpture, we have no recognised standard 
  of authoritative judgment, and bestow sums upon fignre-head cutters and sign-painters
  which might have saved from starving worthy rivals of Phidias and Titian. But who can
  deny to us the glory of being a “ reading people ?” Who can penetrate into our
  kitch- ens, and confute the theory we have established, that our cooks first 
  read, ere they singe their fowls with the sybilline leaves of neglected epics 
  and tragedies, which sputter, as they burn, with a Byronic exultation of scorn 
  for the unappreciating world which shall, too late, lament their incremation 1 
  Who shall deny that our chambermaids draw a refining influence from the fugitive 
  verses which, with an Orphean potency, have taught the savage locks of their 
  mistresses to wander into hyacinthine curls 1 Who but a Pyrrhonist would doubt 
  the existence of those hordes of Nomadic bipliopoles who haunt our railway 
  stations and steamboat-wharves, arrayed, with emblematic propriety, in that 
  last stage of cloth, ere it is transmuted into material for the author and 
  the printer ?</p>
<lb/><p>No, we are emphatically a reading people; but, before making a boast of it, 
  we should do well to consider what we read. Flocks of pamphlets on green, and 
  blue, and yellow wings, hover over the land—obscene volucres—to snatch at and 
  be-slime, like harpies, whatever is pure and healthfully-nourishing for the soul. 
  Under the very eaves of our churches and colleges, these filthy creatures hang their
  nests, prolific of infamy and vice; they perch upon the roofs of our lyceums and
  lecture-rooms ; they disturb the hitherto peaceful recesses of our hamlets and 
  villages with hoarse screams for their prey of garbage and ordure. Literature, 
  in the true sense of the word, is dead; and the only creatures who can be said to
  live by it are the vermin who riot and feast upon its decay. That this state of 
  things is mainly attributable to the want of an international copyright law, we 
  have never had a doubt. It is of the literature which is supplied to the mass of the
  people that we speak— for this the most important. Bad food will produce disease 
  as well in the spiritual as the material world. What a fascinating sound has these
  two words, “ cheap literature !” We fondly imagine the ploughman drinking inspiration
  from his fourpenny Burns, and the cobbler hanging entranced over Bun-yan’s prose 
  translation of Dante. The blacksmith, we think, will swing his sledge to the 
  cadence of a shilling Milton, and Miss Barrett will become the solace of the factory 
  girl for sixpence! Grogshops will be displaced by bookstalls, and, instead of
  “ best liquors at three cents a glass,” we shall see “ Bacon for six cents,” 
  “ Spenser at a shilling,” “ Don Quixotte ten oentaor, if the vender be poetical, 
  he will give u» “ a slice <cb/>
<lb/>of Bacon for fourpence,” “breast of Lamb for sixpence,” “ glass of
  Shakspeare at three cents.” To think of Apollo visiting our floor-hearths
  for eighteen and three-quarter cents, or “ the muses to be seen here ; 
  admittance quarter of a dollar !” But alas! this is but an auctioneer’s
  picture of the beauty of the system. The cabalistic fingers of a George 
  Robbins may be detected pulling the wires of this magnificent fairy-scene.
  The literature which really circulates among the masses, and steals through 
  the gateway of our national morals for so cheap a toll, is the literature of
  the pickpocket, the burglar, and the bawd ; or, if not this, it is the last
  pitiful drivel-lings of sentimentalism in its dotage. We wish that our 
  legislators—whose sinful apathy to the true interests of our literature, 
  and, therefore, of our morals, has created this brazen monster—could be 
  forced to try the involuntary philosophical experiment of Perillus. 
  We wish that they might be made the first tests of the efficiency of
  this system for the education of the people, by being compelled to read 
  all the books which issue from our so-called cheap presses.</p>
  <lb/><p>The book before us is of a very different kind: it is the production
  of a refined and thoughtful scholar. The translator is a clergyman in the 
  neighborhood of Boston, who preaches to a rustic audience sermons worthy of
  the English pulpit when its poetry was supplied by Taylor, and its wit by South.
  A residence in Germany has given him familiarity with the language of his original, 
  and a hearty love of Schiller makes him a worthy translator of its spirit.</p>
  <lb/><p>These letters of Schiller are by no means “ familiar” ones: 
  they are addressed to one of those Princes (Christian Frederick, Duke 
  of Holstein Augustenburg) who took a dilletante interest in the rights 
  of man at the beginning of the French Revolution. Schiller had received
  noble and unexpected aid from him during a period of great distress; and
  though he was a man who could look through the star on the breast to the 
  heart underneath it, yet it is clear that he had only acquired the faculty
  (so hard to gain in aristocratical communities) of looking on his benefactor
  as merely man, and had not yet reached the more unconscious point of
  regarding him as friend. The letters, therefore, are not written with 
  the abandon of private friendship, if, indeed, their subject would have allowed it.</p>
<lb/><p>The translator has prefixed an excellent introduction, written with judgment 
  and eloquence, in which the reader will find a far better analysis of the book
  than we are prepared to give. The following extract from it contains a view of 
  the relation of Goethe and Schiller to each other, which is new to us, and which 
  we deem worthy of attention—as well from its novelty as the exactness and pertinence
  with which it is stated:</p>
<quote type="block"><lb/><p>“ We have lately fallen into the error (for which we are indebted to Germany herself)
  of forcing an unnatural contrast between Goethe and Schiller, her too greatest men. 
  Scholars spend their ingenuity in drawing parallels and exposing differences, when 
  the true process would be, to construct an equation, and indicate the points of 
  contact. The error has become almost irremediable; and it seems to be generally 
  understood, that the two men would have never lived together in Weimar if 
  Providence had not designed to puzzle posterity with the contrast, and to 
  occupy its leisure moments with the debate as to which is the greater. They
  have unfortunately passed into history with the legal versus between their 
  names, which never kept asunder the Doe and Roe of fiction with a more abiding
  pertinacity.</p>
<lb/><p>“This is a great injury which we inflict upon ourselves. 
  Undoubtedly, the delightful period of their common activity
  at Weimar affords the most natural opportunity for instituting
  a j comparison between them, which is not without its interest 
  and advantage. Their mutual tendencies differed too distinctly to 
  escape observation. Perhaps they challenge it; and perhaps the two 
  poets are not worthy as successful exponents of the two great elements
  of humanity—the real and the ideal; for neither was Goethe the whole man,
  nor was Schiller the less
<pb  n="409"/>
<lb/>complete one he has been represented. But it is in this very distinctness
  with which they developed, respectively, those two great elements, that we 
  ought to discern, not only the special mission of each, but the still higher
  mission of both united. It is striking to observe how their diversity produces
  a unity. It would be instructive to analyze their characters, in order to perceive
  their capacity for creating a third character, which is the idea of humanity—the
  result of the two tendencies which make a man. It seems, then, as if that period 
  of their artistic union was a lucky manoeuvre of nature to bring together her two
  elements most favorably developed, that she might ‘ give the world assurance of a man.' 
  Where Goethe was deficient, Schiller abounded; where the latter yearned to express that
  which is absolute, the former fulfilled definite and ascertained limits. Both were
  earnest seekers after truth: it was, for both, the very condition of their existence—
  a demand of their consciousness which they never once evaded. But we attain a steadfast
  form of truth and a harmonious development of human faculties, only by combining
  the results of both ; or, rather, a true man, made after the Divine image, is
  the union of both their tendencies. There will be a residue if we attempt to 
  unite the two men as they were; but, that excepted, the product is the type of
  that which is possible within us, and, as such, it should be prized, studied, 
  and never rudely violated. When German scholars have asked, ‘Which is greater— 
  Goethe ?—Schiller ?’—others have sought to deprecate such a distinction, and 
  have taken refuge in the simile of the Dioscuri ; but even that will not serve
  our turn, for an alternate immortality does not become those who are really
  immortal and available only when made into one.” Pp. 7, 8, 9.</p></quote>
<lb/><p>Elsewhere, Mr. Weiss says, beautifully:—</p>
<lb/><quote type="block"><p>“ The undeniable characters of a good life cannot be denied to Schiller; 
  he is known by his works in every sense. Pure, highminded, truthloving,
  enamored of virtue for her own sweet sake, he presents to us the lofty 
  spectacle of a man pursuing the ideal of his race through every opposition,
  disappointment, loss. He would realize Christianity, which is the moral law
  transfigured by love. In his own person he represents the struggles of humanity;
  his life was an unfinished prophecy. It is inspiring because his deeds were vast,
  and rang like the sound of a trumpet; it is pathetic and purifying because it 
  contained the divine element of sorrow, and we are given to see a spirit, not 
  only battling with the world and with necessities, but wellnigh overmastered with
  its own yearning. He was the direct ambassador of the ideal; he had an indefeasible 
  right to dictate to humanity the terms of its culture, because he evolved it from
  the regenerative idea of duty as love. And what he preached, he practised. * *	*	* 
  His maturer
<lb/>writings present to us his genuine creed and philosophy, and show us his heart
  still honest and pure, still unstormed, though a Titanic intellect had often encamped
  before it.” Pp. 30, 31.</p></quote>
<p><lb/>But Schiller was no apostle of the ideal in the sense which those understand it who would make it an excuse for a weak dereliction from fidelity to the truth of absolute nature. By “ideal,” he meant that highest perfection of nature which only the inspired eye of the true artist can discern. His ideal was not out of the world, but in it. He was not one of those who, not strong enough nor wise enough to follow nature, are inter- ested to make us believe that the region of art is some cloudy realm, the product of their own fancy, and that the beautiful is some misty, undefined shape, which they are pleased to call “ classical,” as if God must give over creating, and go to school to their abecedarian profundity.
</p><p><lb/>Referring the reader again to Mr. Weiss’s excellent intro- duction for an analysis of the book, we proceed to make a few short extracts—such as our space will allow—taken almost at random. We will preface them with the following fit text from the first letter.</p>
<lb/><quote type="block">“ My ideas, drawn rather from a uniform converse with myself than from a rich 
  experience, or from reading, will not deny their origin; they will 
  sooner be guilty of any error than of sectarism, and will rather fall
  from their own weakness than maintain themselves by authority and foreign
  strength.” P. 2.</quote>
<p>  In the following passage, Schiller beautifully describes the aspect 
  under which ancient Greece presented itself to his mind:</p><cb/>
<lb/><quote type="block"><p>“ The Greeks shame us, not only by a simplicity to which our 
  age is a stranger, but they are, at the same time, our rivals —nay, after our model
  —in that very pre-eminence with which we are wont to console ourselves for the native
  perverseness of our manners. At once objective and subjective—at once philosophic and
  creative, tender and energetic—we behold the youth of fancy united in a noble humanity
  to the manliness of reason.</p>
<lb/><p>“ In the beautiful awakening of the spiritual powers at that period, 
  sense and spirit had no strongly-marked peculiarity.* No dispute had yet
  constrained them to withdraw, in a hostile manner, from each other, and 
  define their boundaries. Poesy had not yet contended with wit, and speculation
  had not dis- graced itself by craft. In case of need, both could exchange their
  functions; since each revered truth after its own fashion. However high reason 
  soared, it ever lovingly lifted the outward after it, and however finely and 
  sharply it discriminated, still it never lacerated. It is true it analyzed human 
  nature  and threw its amplified elements into the majestic circle of divinities;
  but not thereby tearing it in pieces, only mingling it diversely, since a complete
  humanity was wanting to no single god. How entirely different with us moderns! With
  us too, the type of the race is thrown, in parts that are amplified, into individuals ;
  but in fragments, not in different combinations; so that one must enquire from 
  individual to individual in order to read collectively the totality of the race. 
  With us, one is almost tempted to affirm, the powers of the mind display themselves
  in experience detached, as they are represented by the psychologist, and we see, 
  not only single subjects, but whole classes of men developing only one part of 
  their dispositions, while the remainder, like stunted plants, preserve vestiges 
  of their nature almost too feeble to be recognised.” Pp. 19-20, Letter 6.</p></quote>
<lb/><p>In the ninth letter, the exuberant stream of Schiller’s eloquence, which has 
  been working its way through the tangled roots and cloven rocks of definitions
  and argumentative premises, with here and there a glassy spot reflecting the sky
  and leaves, or a singing cascade, burst forth free and majestic, and flows on in
  rushing gladness, singing the triumph of its release. We would gladly copy the whole
  of it, had we room. Even  if the translator had not informed us of it in his preface,
  we should have felt sure that this letter was a favorite with him, for it is turned
  into English with admirable fidelity to the meaning, and lucky sympathy with the 
  rhythmic enthusiasm of the original. Throughout the whole book, but particularly in 
  this letter, we feel that translation has been a labor of love and no drudge-work with
  Mr. Weiss. Though our extracts have already been long, we must give our readers one or
  two passages from this letter.</p>
<lb/><quote type="block"><p>“ It is true the Artist is the son of his time, but alas for him if he be
  likewise its pupil, or even its favorite. Let a kind Divinity snatch the suckling
  betimes from his mother’s breast, nourish him with the milk of a bitter age, and 
  let him come to maturity beneath a distant Grecian sky. Then, when he has become a 
  man. let him return, a foreign shape, into his century; not to delight it with his 
  appearance, but terrible, like Agamemnon’s son, to purify it. He will take his 
  material, indeed, from the present, but borrow his form from a nobler time, nay, 
  from beyond all time, from the absolute, unchangeable unity of his being. Here, from
  the pure ether of his Divine nature, runs down the fountain of beauty, undefiled by
  the corruption of races and times which fret far beneath him in troubled whirlpools.</p>
<lb/><p>*****“ But how can the Artist protect himself from the corruptions of his age which
  on all sides surround him ? By despising its judgment. Let him look upward to his 
  dignity and the law, not downward to his prosperity and his wants. Alike free from 
  the vain activity that would fain leave its traces on the fleeting moment, and from 
  the impatient enthusiasm that applies the scale of the absolute to the paltry product
  of time, let him leave to the understanding, which is here at home, the sphere of 
  the actual; but let him strive to evolve the ideal from the union of the possible 
  with the necessary. This let him express in fiction and truth, in the</quote>
<lb/><ab>* We think (with deference to Mr. Weiss’s more thorough knowledge of German) 
  that individuality would better express the meaning here.  Eigenthum is the word 
  in the original.</ab>
  <lb/><pb  n="410"/>
<lb/>play of his fancy and the gravity of his deeds, in all sensible and spiritual 
  forms, and cast it silently into infinite time.” Pp. 36, 37.</p>
<lb/><p>From the essay on Pathos we make one extract containing a criticism which 
  has a wider application than to its immediate object, and which fits many modern
  productions as closely as the old French Drama.</p>
<lb/><quote type="block">“ The latter is the case with the old French Tragedy, in which we are very 
  seldom or never shown a suffering nature, but generally see only cold, declamatory
  poets, or comedians upon stilts. The frosty tone of declamation extinguishes all 
  the nature, and their adorable scenery makes it completely impossible for French 
  tragic poets to portray humanity in its truth. Decency falsifies, even in its own
  proper place, the expression of nature, and yet the art demands the latter 
  imperatively. We can hardly believe it in a French tragic hero that he suffers, 
  for he delivers himself concerning his state of mind like the calmest of men, 
  and his incessant regard to the impression which he makes upon others never allows 
  him to leave to his own nature its freedom. The kings, princesses and heroes of a 
  Corneille and a Voltaire never forget their rank in the most vehement passion, and
  they put off their humanity far sooner than their dignity. They are like the kings
  and emperors in the old picture books, who go to bed with their crowns on.” Pp. 202, 
  203.</quote>
<lb/><p>We must here reluctantly leave a book for which the Translator deserves our
  warmest thanks. It is full to overflowing with deep philosophy, as well of life
  as of morals, with profound criticisms and apothegms upon art, with true poetry,
  the whole all aglow with the warm sunlight of a noble and aspiring nature. It is
  a book, too, which demands study, and which exercises while it instructs. We 
  sincerely hope that Mr. Weiss may be encouraged to persevere in a labor for which
  he has shown such eminent qualifications, and that he will give to the world the
  other volume of translations from Schiller at which he hints in his introduction.</p>
<lb/> <p>Besides the Esthetic letters, the present volume contains essays upon “ The 
  necessary limits in the use of beautiful forms,” “ The moral use of AEsthetic 
  manners,” “ The pathetic,” “ The sublime,” “ The use of the common and low in Art,”
  “Disconnected observations upon various AEsthetic subjects,” “ Upon the tragic art,”
  and “ The philosophical letters.” We learn that it has already been re-published in 
  England.</p></div>
<lb/><div type="section"><head>BOOKS LATELY RECEIVED.</head>
  <lb/><div><head>The<title> Fruit and Fruit Trees of America; or the Culture, Propagation, and 
  Management in the Garden and Orchard, of fruit trees generally. </title>With descriptions 
  of all the finest varieties of fruit, native and foreign, cultivated in this country.
  Illustrated with many engravings. By A. J. Downing. New York and London: Wiley and
  Putnam. 1845.</head>
<lb/><p>This is the most valuable of all the books which Mr. Downing has contributed to
  the higher departments of our rural literature, and it is the most charming book of
  the season, although rather ponderous in dimensions only. Some idea may be formed of
  its completeness from the fact of its containing a list of no less than 490 sorts of
  apples. Mr. Downing claims the right to talk about fruits and trees from having been
  born in “one of the largest gardens, and upon the banks of one of the noblest rivers,
  in America;" every body will concede the right, since he has shown himself so competent
  to his task. “ Fine fruit is the flower of commodities;” and, as Mr. Downing says in
  his preface, “it is the most perfect union of the useful and the beautiful that the 
  earth knows; yet there are many who seem to live under some ban of expulsion from all
  the fair and goodly productions of the garden." But this should not be. Every 
  proprietor of a piece of ground big enough to bleach a pocket handkerchief is bound 
  to cultivate a fruit tree of some kind, if not for himself, for the sake of others; 
  and if there be any <cb/>
<lb/>people who are indifferent to pomological matters, we advise them to procure Mr.
  Downing's work and plunge into the midst of his pearmains, rare-ripes, and damsons. 
  All the true disciples of pomology will get the book, as a matter of course.</p></div>
<lb/><ab>Transactions of the American Ethnological Society : Vol.  1. New York: Bartlett &amp; Welford.
<lb/>Pictorial History of the World. By John Frost, LL. D. Walker &amp; Gillis, No. 5.
<lb/>The Nevilles of Garretstovm: A Tale of 1760. By Charles Lever.
<lb/>New York: E. Winchester, 24 Ann st.
<lb/>The Temptation; or The Watchtower of Koat-Ven. By Eugene Sue. Translated from the French. E. Winchester.
<lb/>The Treasury of History; No. 6. Daniel Adee, 107 Fulton st. Letters from Italy. By J. T. Headley. No. 3 of Wiley and Putnam’s Library of American Books.
<lb/>John Rouge; The Holy Court of Treves and the New German Catholic Church. New York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
<lb/>The Resurrection of Christ; In answer to the question whether He arose in a spiritual and celestial, or in a material and earthly, body. By George Bush. New York; J. S. Redfield, Clinton Hall. 1845.
<lb/>The Mysteries of Berlin : Part 5. W. H. Colyer. New York. Westward, Ho! A Novel. By James K. Paulding. No. 11 of Harpers’ Pocket edition of Select Novels.
<lb/>The Investigator. Edited by J. F. Polk. Devoted to Science, Religion, Literature, &amp;c. Vol. 1, No. 6. Washington : C. Drew. 1845.
<lb/>A Dictionary of Practical Medicine. By James Copland. Edited, with additions, by Charles A. Lee, M. D. Part 9. Harper &amp; Brothers.
<lb/>The Wandering Jew. No. 13.
<lb/>The Pictorial Bible. No. 31.
<lb/>An Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy. No. 6. Harper &amp; Brothers.</ab></div></div>
      <div><lb/><head>FRENCH OPERA AT THE PARK THEATRE.</head>
<p>        <lb/>The French Company, last from New Orleans, is in the second week of its engagement at the above Theatre. The list of its members presents a very formidable array of names, at least in numbers, and, with Calve at the head, it would be supposed sufficient for all purposes of attraction. Whether it will prove so or not, will be determined by and by. Of the merits of the individual members, we shall speak in detail in the course of our notice.
</p>        <lb/><p>One thing we should strongly urge upon Mr. 
        Davis, namely, the absolute necessity of lowering the price of 
        admission to the pit, from one dollar to fifty cents. Not only would 
        the attendance be more than double upon every occasion, but the house 
        would also assume a more lively and brilliant appearance. There are hundreds
        of young men who would willingly go to the Opera every performing night, 
        but who will not pay a dollar, and will not go up stairs to the second tier, 
        and so stay away altogether.</p>
<p>        <lb/>The first opera performed was Guillaume Tell, composed by Rossini. The following was the distribution of characters: Arnold, M. Arnaud; Guillaume Tell, Garry; Walter, Dou-vry; Rodolpbe, Coeuriot; Gesler, Douvry; Melctbal, Bernard; Leuthold, Chaffary; A Fisherman, Pelleve; Princess Mathilde, Mrs. Casini; Jemmy, (son of Guillaume Tell,) Stephen Coeuriot; Edwige, (wife of Guillaume Tell,) Daire; Chorus of officers, pages, Austrian soldiers, Swiss men, women, and children. The plot of Guillaume Tell is so well known on every hand, that we shall not trouble our readers by recapitulating it.
</p>        <lb/><p>In the music, Rossini has in a measure gone from his peculiar 
        and recognised style. The general characteristics are gravity, earnestness,
        and intense passion. There are, of course, many passages of lighter feeling,
        in which we recognise the brilliant and felicitous imagination so peculiar to
        his
        <lb/>410
        <pb  n="411"/>
        <lb/>earlier works; but these are only used as lights to the sombre
        tone which pervades the general subjeet. It is true they are dashed 
        in with the freedom of a master-hand, and fix themselves upon the memory
        at once, from their strong but harmonious contrast.</p>
        <lb/><p>Madame Casini is by no means calculated to sustain an important part in
        a Grand Opera. Her voice is thin and weak, though the upper tones possess some 
        sweetness. Her singing gives evidence of some good schooling, but her style is
        unfinished, and her delivery lacks energy and passion. Her action is constrained
        and awkward, and for a pretty woman, and a French woman, too, she is the most 
        careless dresser we ever saw. The two other ladies, Madame Coeu-riot and Madame
        Dairie, had but little to do, but that little was well done.</p>
        <lb/><p>M. Garry possesses a voice of good quality, but it is sadly deficient 
        in power; it is, however, capable of forcing, particularly in the upper tones.
        M. Garry is a superior artist. He sings with much taste, and in admirable style:
        his modulations are made with a certainty and precision, which stamp him a
        musician as well as a singer. His action is free and vigorous, and altogether, 
        although from want of physical strength, he will never astonish his hearers, he
        will rarely fail to impart pleasure and satisfaction by his general excellence.</p>
        <lb/><p>M. Arnaud is a singer of high merit. He possesses a voice of extraordinary 
        compass and power, and were it as sweet and rich as it is extensive and
        powerful, he would have no equal in the world. His style is admirable—chaste
        and impassioned, and altogether free from vulgarity and affectation. We 
        listened to him with much pleasure from his first appearance, for we immediately 
        perceived that he depended not upon his voice but upon the purity of his school,
        and as soon as our ears became accustomed to the singular quality of his voice,
        we listened to him with the most unqualified delight. He reminds us strongly of
        what Antognini was when he first came to this city. The part of Arnold is one of
        immense difficulty, and we do not hesitate to say that there is no man in the
        country, except M. Arnaud, who would dare to undertake it. M. Arnaud will rise
        in public estimation upon each appearance, and will become a distinguished 
        favorite.</p>
        <lb/><p>Messieurs Douvry, Coeuriot, Bernard, &amp;c. &amp;c., were all
        excellent in their respective parts. We shall have occasion, however, 
        to notice them more fully in other pieces, and to decide upon their merits.</p>
        <lb/><p>The chorus is admirable: undoubtedly the best we have heard on these 
        boards for several years. Everything was given with great precision and power; 
        the trebles were few in number, but they were efficient. The contraltos have 
        capital voices. They are in some parts too powerful for the trebles.</p>
        <lb/><p>The Orchestra is very perfect—composed of fine players, and led by one
        who thoroughly understands his business, M. Prevost. No such orchestra has
        been gathered together within the walls of a theatre for many years. It was 
        a pleasure to observe with what admirable faithfulness the beautiful points 
        in the instrumentation were brought out in strong relief. Nothing was lost,
        nothing was obscured. We are glad to be able to award to the members, 
        individually, and to the leader of the orchestra, our unqualified approbation.</p>
        <lb/><p>The piece was brought out with great magnificence, and with due attention
        to time and locality. The scenery, especially the set scenes, was beautiful,
        and the costumes were carefully selected according to the date.</p>
        <lb/><p>As a whole the performance was good, and well worthy the liberal
        patronage of the public.</p>
        <lb/><p>There are several omissions which we might mention, but we 
        presume that they were omitted from necessity.</p><cb/>
        <lb/><p>Auber’s Opera Les Diamans de Couronne, was chosen for 
        the re-appearance of Mad’lle Calve, after an absence of two years.</p>
        <lb/><p>The distribution of the Opera was as follows: Caterino, Mad’lle Calve; 
        Diana, Mad. Stephen Coeuriot; Don Hen-rique, M. Coeuriot; Don Sebatien, M. 
        Buscher; Rebolledo. M. Bernard; Camp Mayor, M. Mathieu.</p>
        <lb/><p>Mad’lle Calve was received most warmly. She has improved in 
        personal appearance since she was here last. She has lost none of 
        her fascination of manner, but on the contrary, seems to have made 
        the charm more powerful. She was dressed to perfection, and wore her 
        dresses with an air and grace peculiar to herself, and rarely attained
        by any one else. Her school of singing we never did admire—it is false,
        meritricious and flashy: but Calve sings well in her school, and for that
        she should have all praise. Indeed Calve seems to have been destined for 
        the school of which Auber is the bead, for her aril, piquant, and playful 
        manner adds a charm and a grace to that most charming and graceful class 
        of composition. Calve’s performance upon this occasion was in truth all 
        that could be desired, and won for her, besides the hearty plaudits of the
        audience, a whole host of bouquets.</p>
        <lb/><p>Madame Stephen Coeuriot somewhat surprised us upon this occasion. 
        From her performance in Guillaume Tell we were convinced that she had 
        talent, but we hardly gave her credit for so much excellence as she 
        displayed on Friday night. She has a melodious and sufficiently powerful
        voice, and uses it like an article. Her costumes are in admirable taste,
        and are worn with much grace. She acts well and looks well, and in short
        she supplies, very nearly, the place in public estimation which Madame Le 
        Compt held loo years since.</p>
        <lb/><p>M. Coeuriot is equally excellent in his way. He possesses a light 
        and pleasing tenor voice, with a carefully cultivated and well-managed 
        falsetto. He sings with much taste and judgment, and is an actor of 
        considerable merit. He is a great acquisition to the company.</p>
        <lb/><p>M. Buscher is a careful and well-educated singer, but his voice
        is weak, and his action is tame and timid.</p>
        <lb/><p>M. Bernard is truly comic: his humor is unobtrusive, but it is so 
        dry and earnest that it becomes infectious. He is besides a very careful
        singer and capital actor.</p>
        <lb/><p>The other parts were very creditably sustained. The chorus was 
        exceedingly good throughout—indeed, so good that it became a feature.</p>
        <lb/><p>The performance of the orchestra was admirable throughout —even more
        perfect than upon the occasion of Guillaume Tell. We have rarely heard
        accompaniments more faithfully and distinctly rendered. M. Prevost and 
        the gentleman of the orchestra shared equally the just admiration of the 
        public.</p>
        <lb/><p>The music, by Auber, is singularly beautiful. From the beginning to 
        the end, it is a series of brilliant thoughts, worked out in a masterly 
        manner. Quite original, after the style of Auber, its quaintness immediately
        strikes the most indifferent observer. Its melodies are indeed ravishingly
        beautiful; it is richly harmonised, and its distinguishing characteristic 
        is never lost sight of.</p>
        <lb/><p>The Instrumentation is perfect. More or less beautiful and startling 
        effects and charming contributions are found in every piece. Their number 
        surprises us, their novelty delights us, and we admiringly acknowledge Auber
        to be the most ingenious and effective orchestral writer among the modern 
        operatic composers of Europe.</p>
        <lb/><p>We cordially recommend the French Operatic Company to our musical 
        friends.</p>
        <lb/><p>La Favorite, composed by Donizetti, was produced on Wednesday last. 
        We shall notice it in our next.</p>
        <pb  n="412"/></div>
<lb/><div><head>THE FINE ARTS.
</head><lb/><p>We were invited to examine the portrait of the new packet ship Henry Clay, 
  painted by Mr. Marsh, of Boston, who has certainly succeeded in giving a very striking
  likeness of this noble ship; his water, however, is the best part of the picture.
  In other marine paintings that we have seen, the water has been painted as though 
  it were an accessory, instead of being a principal, element in a sea scene. The
  ship is represented under full sail, with the wind on the quarter, and a fore-topmast
  studding sail set. There is a distant view of the Highlands of Neversink and Sandy 
  Hook. We understand that the painting is intended for a present to Mr. Clay from the 
  owners of the ship.</p>
<lb/><p>We remember Mr. Marsh as the author of a volume of poems which were published 
  in this city a few years since; but we have never heard of him before as a marine 
  painter.</p>
<lb/><p>Mr. Alfred Jones, the engraver of “Sparking,” one of the Art-Union issues, 
  has just published a handsome engraving of the Capitol, at Washington. The 
  view is taken from Pennsylvania Avenue, and represents the back part of the 
  Capitol, with the noble terraces, fountain, &amp;c. It makes a very handsome
  picture; but, being an enlargement of the small drawing by Bartlett, in the
  views of American scenery published by Martin, it is rather meagre in the 
  details for so large an engraving.</p>
</div><lb/><div><head>WEEKLY NOTES.</head>
<lb/><p>A novel has recently been published by Colburn, in London, called 
  “Jonathan Sharp, or the Adventures of a Kentuckian,” which is professedly 
  written by an American, but the fact is questioned by a critic in the 
  Athenaeum for the following reasons:</p>
<lb/><quote type="block">“ Beyond the Alleghanies, Lynch law is too rife and too supreme; and, even in 
  an Atlantic city, such a moral censor would find his post so little enviable as
  to be in some hurry to quit it. He might, to be sure, come to England, as the
  author in question professes to have done, and published whatever he pleased.
  But could the pure love of truth, or the patriotic view of scolding his countrymen 
  into belter manners, be a sufficient inducement ? Besides, to expect an American, 
  whose self love and national pride surpass those of any people on earth, so to 
  divest himself of his nature as to view things through an European glass is absurd.”</quote>
<lb/><p>The reviewer surmises that Jonathan Sharp is an Irishman ; but, from his close
  intimacy with the peculiarities of Western manners, we are inclined to believe that
  he is what he professes, a genuine United Stateser, but not a Kentuckian. He must,
  however, be a very bad fellow, so to libel his countrymen as to call forth such a 
  rebuke as this from an English critic, whose remarks prove him to be neither well
  informed on American subjects, nor well disposed towards the country.</p>
<lb/><quote type="block">" In almost every page he evinces his personal and intimate acquaintance with his
  subject. But that he is invariably as honest as he is well informed, is a very
  different subject. The soreness which he displays in every chapter, can be the 
  result only of personal disappointment. If, in most instances, he has truth for 
  the foundation of his statements, he takes good care to stretch it as far as it 
  will bear—sometimes a little farther. What justice is there in an author who 
  condemns a New Englander for vices which are found to exist only when we come to 
  the Valley of the Mississippi, &amp;c.”</quote>
<lb/><p>The Englishman has a strange view of American morals, if he thinks that
  violence of any kind would be offered to any man, on this side the Atlantic,
  for speaking his opinions freely of the national manners or vices. Abuse of
  every kind may be uttered with such “ perfect looseness” that satire and irony
  have lost their uses with us. We have neither Punches nor Charlvaris iu America,
  for the reason that there is no need of <cb/>
<lb/> them. It would be idle to satirise a vice which can be boldly
<lb/>exposed.</p>
<p><lb/>We can suggest a better reason for the author of Jonathan  Sharp having published his adventures in London than the Athenaeum has given: probably he could not find a publisher in America, and was too poor to undertake the publication himself.
</p><lb/><p>The last number of Tait’s Magazine contains a very generous and discriminating
  Review of the “Poems on Mao in the Republic,” by Cornelius Matthews ; and the Athenaeum
  has a funny notice of the “Letters from a Landscape Painter,” by Charles Lanman. Mr. 
  Cole, and the other artists who had the ill fortune to be served up by Mr. Lanman,
  form  the subjects of a good many witty jokes, while Mr. Lanman’s  Burlington friends,
  who gave such capital dinners, and were, withal, such perfect scholars and gentlemen,
  come in for their share of fun.</p>
</div><lb/><div><head>A MEMORY OF THOMAS HOOD.
<lb/>BY MRS S. C. HALL.</head>
  <lb/><p>The past winter has been one of dismal heaviness to us, for  it has been so 
  to many dear friends ; a cold bleak “ season ”— each month surpassing its predecessor 
  in the number of its bereavements, until we have asked each other, “ Is the cup of 
  sorrow yet unfilled ?” All through February and March the dull boom of the death-bell
  mingled with the snow-wreath and rose above the storm, while the frost-bound earth 
  echoed the clank of the mattock and the spade. We do not speak of the simple hearts, 
  near and dear, whom death found as fittest for immortality—ripest for the sickle—but
  of others, known to the world about us, who have been taken “ home” in the flower of 
  their days; and more especially of one, just gone, whose gentle spirit past away while
  nature was recruiting,—resuming  her leaves and flowers, and wearing once again a
  happy look of plenteousness and peace.</p>
  <lb/> <p>First, from over the sea, came news of the death of one who, if longer spared,
  would have achieved a much higher reputation than she had yet won—for her mind was 
  evidently gaining strength, and her views of life and knowledge of literature were 
  expanding. One of our contemporaries has said,  that Mary Anne Browne was “ spoiled 
  at first by over-praise;"  over-praised the girl-poet might have been, but none who
  have read what she has written as Mrs. James Gray, could have deemed her “spoiled”—
  for all her later works evince care  and thought, and much genuine refinement; and 
  her last small  volume of poems—“ Sketches from the Antique ”—supply ev- idence of 
  higher hopes and holier aspirations than belong to the  “ spoiled ” children of the 
  Muses. Her short life, though  uneventful, was chequered and of uneven course—as 
  literary  lives always are in England—but she was a loving and a be- loved wife, 
  esteemed by those who knew her as a kind and amiable woman, and one of rare industry. 
  I found it hard to  believe that death had taken her from the new-born infant that 
  nestled in her bosom ; that the grave had closed over the  laughing girl I had seen 
  but as yesterday—her rich brown  curls clustering round her throat, and her eyes 
  luminous with mirth.</p>
  <lb/> <p>But heavier sorrows followed. There are few, indeed, who are acquainted with 
  the light and graceful literature of our country—who cull the simple and natural
  flowers so plentifully scattered in their paths—to whom the name of Laman Blanchard
  is unknown: his ready and eloquent pen could indite a sonnet, point an epigram, tell
  a story, or lend interest to  an essay, while slower spirits were wondering and 
  pondering what they had to write about.</p>
  <lb/><p>His name was a pleasant watchword, a guarantee that some-thing was to follow
  —racy and fanciful. His wit, rather genial than caustic, and so abounding that it
  brightened everything it played about, was checked only by a sensible desire to 
  avoid giving pain; even where to censure became a duty, this  tenderness in his nature
  was apparent in his writings : he frequently stopped short of his object lest he might 
  inflict a wound. Of late, few articles bore his name in periodical works ; and 
  those who are unacquainted with the mighty me-chanism that scatters “ leaders,”
  “ criticisms,” and “ reviews,” —“ opinions ” of all kinds on all subjects to guide 
  the multi-tude,—little imagine what volumes have passed down the stream of time—
  written for “ the day,” by this man of many
  <pb  n="413"/>
<lb/>labors, but upon which the power of the throbbing brain had been lavishly expended.</p>
<lb/><p>Sixteen years ago we knew him; ever as a poet, bouyant with youth and hope—his 
  purpose fixed, his independence unflinching—with the dreamy, ardent temperament of
  a genuine “ child of song,” yet turning himself to the direst and hardest duty work,
  and laboring at everything that did not compromise the principles with which he set 
  out in life,—fighting his way with a brave heart and a bright eye, known only to be 
  loved, and imparting as much pleasure to, as he received from, literary society. Many
  are the happy and profitable hours we have passed together; his ready sympathy 
  attracting confidence that was never betrayed. Alas ! his wife became the victim 
  of a distressing malady; and his sensitive nerves were ill able to endure long 
  midnight watchings, relieved only by midnight labor—the coin with which genius 
  purchases bread. She died some months ago, and to all but him her death seemed a 
  mer-cy. From that time, however, his light of life either blazed or flickered, as 
  it was excited. He rose up, and went about, and wrote, when he could, but fancied,
  and perhaps truly, that he could not write as he had done. The fact was, his mind 
  required repose—a total absence from labor—it craved rest; but how is the producer
  of periodical literature to find rest ? People tell you “ not to be excited,”
  “ not to overwork your- self.” Ah ! they cannot see underneath the gay draperies 
  that society folds around the form—they cannot see the chains that bind us to the 
  galley. A terror that he should be unable to provide for his children took hold of
  our poor friend—seized him by the brain through the heart; his eyes became affect-ed
  —to all appearance they were as bright as ever, but he could not endure the light, 
  and continued to suffer intensely ; his imagination appeared to retain its power after
  his reason had given way ; and thus was the fountain of life exhausted at one-and-
  forty! The eloquent and tender poet—the man with many real friends, yet dying in
  harness which, if one ready hand had unbuckled for a time, might have been worn, 
  after a brief rest, in honor for many years! Not but he was difficult to manage ; 
  loathe to owe any debt save to his own exertions; and proud—as all right-thinking 
  men must be—of the independence that had won the respect and friendship of the 
  intellectual and the true ; and it was hard, when you saw his bright face or heard
  his pleasant words, to think of him and sorrow the sure suggestion was, that he 
  would be better by-and-by. Ah! it was a mournful termination to such a life.</p>
<lb/><p>And, after he was laid in his grave, the bells tolled on; another and another 
  passed away—names highly honored in Art —Calcott, Smirke, Phillips, the gentle 
  and highly-gifted Duncan ; and now one whose name has long been a household word,
  but whose death has been anticipated for months, say, for years—the noble poet—yet, 
  strange to say, better known as the annual “jester”—Thomas Hood! Truly, the man who,
  year after year, furnished abundant food for mirth, and yet could imagine “The Plea
  of the Midsummer Fairies,”
<lb/>“ The Dream of Eugene Aram,” and depict such realities as “ The Song of a Shirt,” 
  and “ The Bridge of Sighs,” must have been formed in no common mould ! He, too, 
  is gone “ home!”</p>
<lb/><p>I remember the first time I met him was at one of the pleasant soirees of the 
 painter Martin ; for a moment I turned away —as many have done—disappointed, for
 the countenance, in repose, was of melancholy rather than of mirth : there was 
 something calm, even to solemnity, in the upper portion of the face, which, in 
 public, was seldom relieved by the eloquent play of the mouth, or the occasional 
 sparkle of the observant eye; and it was a general remark among his acquaintances,
 that he was too quiet for “ the world.” There are many wit-watchers to be found in
 society, who think there is nothing in a man, unless, like a sounding-board, he 
 make a great noise at a small touch,—who consider themselves aggrieved, unless 
 an “author” open at once like a book, and speak as he writes ; this vulgar notion,
 like others of the same stamp, creeps into good society, or that is so considered, 
 and I have seen both Hook and Hood “ set,” as a pointer sets a partridge, 
 by persons who glitter in evanescent light simply by repeating what such men
 have said. Mr. Hook, perhaps, liked this celebrity —this setting and staring,
 this lion hunt—so different from the heart-worship paid to veritable greatness.
 Mr. Hood did not: he was too sensitive, too refined, to endure it; the dislike 
 to being pointed at as the “ man who was funny,” kept him out of a crowd, where
 there were always numbers who really honored his genius, and loved him for his 
 gentle and domestic virtues. It was only among his friends that his playful fancy
<cb/><lb/>flourished, or that he yielded to its influence ; although, strictly
  speaking, “ social ” in all his feelings, he never sought to stimulate his wit
  by the false poison of draughts of wine ; nor was he ever more cheerful than 
  when at his own fireside he enjoyed the companionship of his dear and devoted 
  wife. He was playful as a child ; and his imagination, pure as bright, frolicked
  with nature, whom he loved too well ever to outrage or insult by slight or 
  misrepresentation. And yet he was City born, and City bred,—born in the
  unpoetic district of “ the Poultry;” though born as it were, to letters, for 
  his father was a bookseller ; and the son was remarkable for great vivacity of
  spirits, and prone to astonish good citizens, guests at his father’s, no less 
  than his fellow-pupils when at school, by the shrewdness and brilliancy of his 
  observations upon topics of which it was thought he knew nothing. He finished 
  his education at Camberwell; and, even at that early age being in very precarious
  health, was advised to try the effects of a sea voyage upon his constitution. 
  The sea suited him not. I can well imagine its boiling turbulence—its fitfulness—
  its glittering brightness, and its fearful storms finding no sympathy in the 
  gentle bosom of the author of “ The Plea of the Midsummer Fairies.”</p>
<lb/><p>He passed some years, on his retnrn, with relatives in “ Bonny Dundee and,
  manifesting a great talent for drawing, was apprenticed to his uncle, Mr.
  Robert Sands, an engraver. But he trifled with the pencil, while he labored 
  with the pen; his future destiny was pointed out by the light of genius. And what
  rare talents did he not possess, blended with the gentleness and kindliness of the
  sweetest of poetic temperaments— how full his sympathies !—how honest his heart—
  how great and true in all things! Although his existence was a long disease rather
  than a life, he was free from all bitterness and harshness of spirit, feeling 
  intensely for the sufferings of others ; he was in every way unselfish ; prone 
  to the very last to turn his own sad sufferings into jests, and forcing those 
  who wept over his agony, fierce as it was (until the last dull sleep which continued
  from the Tuesday to the Saturday of his death), to smile at the wittiness of his 
  conceits, mingling as they did with a touching consciousness of his situation, 
  and the solemn belief that hereafter which, in all faith and humility, we 
  believe—to the full extent of knowledge—he now enjoys.</p>
<lb/><p>But what a sad picture—and by no means a solitary one— do the last months
  of this great man’s life display !	“ The
<lb/>Song of a Shirt ” was knocking at every heart in Great Britain,
  while its author was panting for breath, and trying to enlist the forces
  of his friends in the launch of the Magazine that still bears his name.
  And his friends stood by him : they gathered willingly beneath the banner,
  which, had it been raised by a strong arm instead of one trembling with pain 
  and the unsteadiness of departed health, would have battled the breeze nobly 
  and waved for years triumphantly above—as a shelter to—his home. A little 
  longer, and the difficulties of his position increased ; one illness succeeded 
  another, and “ l’Envoi ” to the end of each “ periodical labor ” induced the mingled 
  smiles and tears of his admirers. He wrote wit while propped by pillows; and
  the chapters of a novel—doomed to remain, like his life, a great fragment—were
  produced between the intervals and beatings of heart disease.</p>
<lb/><p>Alas ! what those endure who write for bread ! But it is all over with him now :
  the gold has been refined and the crucible is broken ; the toilworn body has been
  bowed in death that the soul might escape into life ; the mortal cerements have been
  burst; the winged child is borne into the true life—the life of eternity! Those
  who loved him best rejoice at his release from labor—never remunerated in proportion
  to the pleasure it gave—never in a way at all commensurate with the enormous 
  profit it produced—seldom, perhaps, thought of by those whose hearts it opened.
  Latterly his dear friends had been agonized by his terrible lament, “ I cannot die—
  I cannot die!” Such friends were thankful to lay him, on the 10th of May, in a
  calm grave at Kensall-green. It will not, we are sure, be long before a monument
  is raised to his memory ; and there are hearts enough in England to remember that
  his widow and two children have but the hundred a year to subsist on —bestowed by
  Sir Robert Feel, whose letter, in words which did him honor, conveyed the request
  that he might be permitted to make the personal acquaintance of one whose works he
  had long admired and appreciated. In this generous wish and hope he was destined to
  be disappointed,—but
<lb/>Honor and glory to a great statesman with a good heart ! Such men are
  worthy almoners of genius!</p>
<pb  n="414"/></div>
<lb/><div><head>NEW WORKS PUBLISHED IN LONDON, MAY, 1845
</head><lb/><ab>Aide Memoire to the Military Sciences. By officers of the different services. 89 plates, 40 wood-cuts.
<lb/>Anderson (Christopher) Annals of the English Bible. 2 vols. 8vo. Bremer (Miss) Life in Dalecarlia. Translated by W. Howitt. Balmer, Academical Lectures and Pulpit Discourses. 2 vols. 8vo. Book of Ballads. Edited by Bon Gaultier. Illustrated by Crow-quill.
<lb/>Barrow, Naval Worthies of the Reign of Queen Elizabeth.
<lb/>Bourne (J. G. H.) England Won. A poem.
<lb/>Clayton, Child’s First Drawing-Book.
<lb/>Crompton (Susan F.) Stories for Sunday Afternoons, from the Creation to the Advent of Messiah.
<lb/>Child (Mrs.) Letters from New-York, second series.
<lb/>Cumming (Rev. John) " Our Father," a Week’s Family Prayers. Course ol Lectures to Young Men, delivered in Dundee.
<lb/>Craik (George L.) Sketches of the History of Literature and Learning in England, third series, from 1688 to the present time. Davidsou, (C. E.) on the Improvement of Tidal Rivers.
<lb/>Days and Nights in the East, from original notes of a recent traveller through Egypt, Arabia Petrae, &amp;c.
<lb/>Dickinson, (Bishop) Remains. 8vo.
<lb/>Denham, (T.) Poems and Sketches of Prose. 8vo.
<lb/>Disputed Inheritance, (The) a novel, by Grace Webster.
<lb/>Dower, Short Atlas of Modern Geography.
<lb/>Economy, or a Peep at our Neighbors. 8vo.
<lb/>Egan, (C.) Observations on the new French Law of Patents for Inventions.
<lb/>Family Sanctuary, a Form of Domestic Devotion for every Sabbath in the year.
<lb/>Foot Family in Ireland, a novel.
<lb/>Fergusson, (James) Description of the Rock-cut Temples of India. 8 vo.
<lb/>Foster, (John) Lectures delivered at Broadmead Chapel, Bristol. Glenny, Gardening for the Million. 18mo.
<lb/>Hill, (Rev. G. D.) Sermons on the Ten Commandments.
<lb/>Howard, (J. E.) Eight Lectures on the Scriptural Truths opposed by Puseyism.
<lb/>Hand Book of Foreign Cookery. 8vo.
<lb/>Hall, (Mrs. S. C.) The White Boy, a story of Ireland in 1822. Inman, (W. S.) Essay on Symbolical Colors.
<lb/>Leatham, (W. H.) Lectures delivered at Literary and Mechanics’ Institutions.
<lb/>Lappenbergh’s Anglo-Saxon History, translated from the German.
<lb/>2 vols. 8vo.
<lb/>Letters selected from the Correspondence of Helen Plumptre. Lister, (C.) College Chums, a novel. 2 vols.
<lb/>MacBriar, (Rev. R. M.) Chapters on National Education. 8vo. Mass and Rubrics of the Roman Catholic Church, translated into English by the Rev. John Cotter, A. M.
<lb/>Neison, (F. G. P.) Contributions to Vital Statistics, a development of the Rate of Mortality and the Laws of Sickness. 4to.
<lb/>OEdipus Tyrannus of Sophocles, with notes. By T. Mitchell, A. M. 8vo.
<lb/>Orphan Boy, (The) by Mary Elliott.
<lb/>Peats, (Rev. J.) Sapphic Odes of Horace. 12mo.
<lb/>Perfect Peace, Letters memorial of the late J. W. Howell. By Rev. D. Pitcairn ; and Introduction, by Rev. J. Stephenson.
<lb/>Rush, (R.) Residence at the Court of London, second series. 2 vols. 8vo.
<lb/>Roberts, (Mary) Flowers of the Matin and Even Song.
<lb/>Sermons to his late Parishioners, by Bishop Thomas, of Frederick-ton. 12mo.
<lb/>Smith, (C. H.) Observations on Stones used for Building, with 7 plates. 4to.
<lb/>Smith, (Thomas) On Acute Hydrocephalus, or Water-Brain Fever.
<lb/>8vo.
<lb/>Souvenir of the Bristol Chess Club. 12mo.
<lb/>Spence, (Rev. J.) Christ the Christian's God and Saviour. Stephens’s Ecclesiastical Institutes and Eleemosynary Institutions.
<lb/>2 vols. 8vo.
<lb/>Strzelecki, Physical Description of New South Wales and Van Dieman’s Land, plates. 8vo.
<lb/>Smith, (G.) Perilous Times, or the Aggressions of Anti-Christian Error on Scriptural Christianity. 12mo.
<lb/>Tales of the Trains, by Tilbury Tramp: a series of books adapted for the amusement of railway and other travellers.
<lb/>Tait, (Rev. W.) Meditationes Hebraica, an Exposition of the Epistle of Paul to the Hebrews. 2 vols. 8vo.
<lb/>Twiss,- (T.) On Certain Tests of a Thriving Population. 8vo. Waddington, (George) Three Lectures on National Education, delivered at Newcastle, on Tyne. 8vo.
<lb/>Walpole, (Horace) Memoirs of the Reign of George III. Edited, with Notes, by Sir Dennis Le Merchant, (concluding volumes.) Ulrich, a tale. By Ida, Countess Hahn-Hahn.
<lb/>Urling, (R. W.) Laws of Patents in Foreign Countries.
<lb/>Upsal, (Archbishop of) Review of the present state of the Church, translated from the Swedish of Christ.
<lb/>Winer, (Dr. G. B.) Grammar of the Idioms of the Greek language of the New Testament.
</ab></div><cb/><lb/><div type="section"><head>INTERESTING WORKS
<lb/>JUST PUBLISHED BY
<lb/>HARPER &amp; BROTHERS, NEW-YORK.</head>
<lb/><div><ab>THE NEW REFORMATION.
<lb/>Now ready, with curious Illustrative Plate, price 25 cents, or Muslin, 371/2 cents.
<lb/>JOHN RONGE,
<lb/>THE HOLY COAT OF TREVES,
<lb/>AND THE NEW GERMAN CATHOLIC CHURCH.</ab>
<lb/><p>Including authentic details of the events connected with the recent 
  exhibition of the pretended " Coat of our Lord” in the Cathedral of Treves,
  during the months of August and September, 1844: comprising the letters and
  protestations of the author against the imposition and superstitions of the 
  Roman Catholic priests, &amp;c.</p>
<lb/><p>This publication is exceedingly opportune : it will be perused with deep
  interest by the Protestant community at large.—Commercial Advertiser.</p>
<lb/><p>The noble protest of Ronge has been circulated in Germany, not by thousands,
  but by millions of copies; and it has been hailed with loud applause by all 
  classes, because it expresses a public sentiment, and finds a response in all
  hearts.—New York Observer.</p>
<lb/><ab>PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES.
<lb/>In one volume, 12mo., beautifully printed, price 75 cts.
<lb/>A PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES,
<lb/>THROUGH THE VALLEY
<lb/>OF THE MEUSE, AND THE FOREST OF ARDENNES.
<lb/>BY CHARLES EDWARD ANTHON, Esq.</ab>
<lb/><p>This is the production of a young American, who had the rare fortune 
  to be present at the most marvellous occurrence of the 19th century—the
  exhibition of the Holy Robe. In addition to a very graphic description of
  this extraordinary event, which, from the excitement it has created, seems
  destined to be an era in the Christian Church, this unpretending volume is 
  replete with antiquarian lore, relating to the city of Charlemagne, from 
  which the Pilgrimage” commences—the intermediate historic and poetic ground;
  and of the once renowned city of Treves, with which it closes. It is the work
  of a scholar, and cannot fail to enlist a profound interest.— Oswego Advertiser</p>.</div>
<lb/><div><head>MR. PRESCOTT’S HISTORICAL WORKS.</head>
<lb/><ab>In 3 volumes 8vo, beautifully printed, and accompanied with fine Engravings.
<lb/>HISTORY OF
<lb/>THE CONQUEST OF MEXICO,
<lb/>WITH A LIFE OF THE CONQUEROR, HERNANDO CORTES AND A VIEW OF ANCIENT MEXICAN CIVILIZATION.
<lb/>BY WILLIAM H. PRESCOTT, Esq.</ab>
<lb/><p>Mr. Prescott appears to possess almost every qualification for his
  task ; he has a pure, simple, and eloquent style—a keen relish for the
  picturesque—a quick and discerning judgment of character, and a calm, 
  generous, and enlightened spirit of philanthropy. There is no exaggeration
  in stating that his " Conquest of Mexico” contains most of the valuable 
  qualities which distinguish the most popular historical writers in our 
  language of the present day. It unites the chivalrous but truthful 
  enthusiasm of Col. Napier, and the vivacity of the accomplished author 
  of the “ Siege of Granada,” with the patient and ample research of Mr. 
  Tytler.—Edinburgh Review, May, 1845.</p>
<lb/><ab>In 3 volumes 8vo, uniform with the above, with Portraits and Maps.
<lb/>HISTORY OF THE
<lb/>REIGN OF FERDINAND AND ISABELLA,
<lb/>THE CATHOLIC.
<lb/>BY WILLIAM H. PRESCOTT, Esq.
<lb/>The Tenth Edition.</ab>
<lb/><p>It would be altogether supererogatory to make this celebrated work
  the subject of critical analysis, since it has so long been distinguished
  by the concurrent and enthusiastic applause of the whole reading community.
  We know of scarcely any other work so amusing, instructive, and powerfully 
  attractive as the " History of Ferdinand and Isabella;” it possesses every 
  charm which elegance of diction, gracefulness of style, and interest of 
  subject can impart. In a word, it is such a production as could only have
  emanated from a mind richly stored with the wealth of sound learning, genius,
  and the felicitous art of its application.—N. Y. Review.</p>
<pb  n="415"/></div></div>
<lb/><div type="section"><head>JUST PUBLISHED,
<lb/>WILEY &amp; PUTNAM’S
<lb/>LIBRARY OF AMERICAN BOOKS.
</head><lb/><div><head>JOURNAL OF AN AFRICAN CRUISER.</head>
<lb/><p><title>Journal or an African Cruiser</title>; comprising Sketches of the Canaries, the Cape de
  Verdes, Liberia, Madeira, Sierra Leone, and other places of interest on the West
  Coast of Africa. By an Officer of the U. S. Navy. Edited by Nathaniel Hawthorne.
  50 cents.</p></div>
<lb/<div>><head>II.
<lb/>POE’S TALES.</head>
<lb/><p><title>Tales</title>. By Edgar A. Poe. 50 cents.
<lb/>This excellent collection will include the most characteristic of the peculiar series of Tales written by Mr. Poe. Among others will be found “ The Murders of the Rue Morgue,’’ “ The Purloined Letter," “ Marie Roget,” “ The House of Usher,” “ William Wilson," “ The Gold Bug,” “ The Descent into the Maelstrom,” “ The Premature Burial, “ Mesmeric Revelations,” &amp;c., &amp;c.
</p></div><lb/><div><head>III.
<lb/>LETTERS FROM ITALY.
<lb/>BY J. T. Headley. 50 cts.</head>
<lb/><ab>Contents.—Voyage to Italy—Man Lost Overboard ; Gibraltar —Approach to Geneva; First Impressions—Lunatics; Description of Genoa; House-Hunting—Romantic Marriage; Funeral in the Morning—Murder of an American Officer; Carnival—Clara Novel-lo—Persecution of a Painter; Columbus’ Manuscrips—Horseback Ride—Death in the Theatre; A Day's Ramble through Genoa; Italian Soirees and Beauty—Marquis of Palavicini, &amp;c., &amp;c. Published and for sale by	WILEY &amp; PUTNAM,
<lb/>161 Broadway.</ab></div></div>
<lb/><div><head>LONDON AND PARIS LITERARY AGENCY-
<lb break="no"/>O. Rich &amp; SONS.
<lb/>A GENTS FOR THE PURCHASE OF BOOKS FOR
<lb/>AMERICA.</head>
<lb/><ab>Agents for the Library of Congress,
<lb/>The New-York Society Library.
<lb/>The Albany Institute,
<lb/>The Boston Athenaeum, &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c.
<lb/>12 Red Lion Square, London.
<lb/>12 Rue Pot de Per. Paris.</ab>
<lb/><p>Mr. Rich Respectfully informs his friends and fellow-citizens that he has
  formed an establishment in Paris, in connexion with his old estab-lishment in 
  Red Lion Square, for the purpose of furnishing BOOKS published on the continent
  without the heavy expense attending their transmission through England. Each of 
  these establishments will be conducted by one of his sons, under his own general
  superintendence.— This new arrangement, he trusts, will prove of signal advantage
  to his correspondents, and no exertions will be wanting to execute their orders
  on the most advantageous terms. Orders may be sent through, and small sums payed
  to Messrs. Goodhue &amp; Co. of New-York. Two and a half percent will be allowed
  to all those who make a remittance with their orders.</p>
<lb/><p>Mr. Rich, having made Bibliography his special study for forty years, 
  possesses a knowledge of books and editions not often to be met with, and 
  will be happy to give any advice and information respecting the formation 
  of Libraries or Collections of Books in any particular branch of literature
  or science. For information in regard to his efficiency, he begs to refer to
  Messrs. Prescott, Ticknor, Sparks, Irving, and other literary characters in 
  the United States, to whom he is known. Intending to devote the remainder of 
  hie life to literary pursuits, his greatest pleasure will arise from sending 
  rare and valuable books to his own country ; and he trusts to live long enough
  to see in the United States a Library which may bear a comparison with the most
  celebrated in Europe. If he can live to say, “ I also assisted IN its Formation,” 
  his most ardent wishes will be gratified.</p>
<lb/><p>Mr. Rich has in press—Bibliotheca Americana Nova: a Catalogue of Books 
  relating to America, including Voyages to the South Seas and round the World 
  : Part III. from 1831 to 1845, with supplement and index completing the work.</p>
<lb/><p>He has also ready for the press, Bibliotheca Americana Vetus: a Catalogue 
  of Books relating to America from the discovery to the year 1700 ; with notes
  and observations : in one vol, 8 vo., of about 400 pages.</p>
<lb/><p>Mr Rich has also ready a reprint from Thevenot's Collection of Fath-er
  Marquette’s account of the discovery of the Mississippi, entitled,
<lb/>' Decouverte de quelques Pays et Nations de l'Amerique Septentrionale.’ 
  Only 125 copies are printed, which will be distributed among Mr. Rich's 
  friends and correspondents.</p>
<lb/><p>Mr. Rich has also purchased the remaining copies of the part relating
  to America of L'Art de Verifier les Dates; of which ten volumes in octavo,
  by D. B- Warden, Esq., are printed, and two volumes more, completing the work,
  will be published during the course of the present year.</p>
<lb/><ab>Price of the ten volumes published, ....	40 francs
<lb/>Complete sets of the Art de Verifier les Dates, in 44 vols. 8vo, 160 francs, instead of 308, the original price.
<lb/>Paris, May 1,1845.	may24</ab></div><cb/>
<lb/><div><head>The National Magazine and Industrial Record, No. I.</head>
<lb/><ab>EDITED BY REDWOOD FISHER,
<lb/>ASSISTED IN THE STATISTICAL DEPARTMENT BY MR. EDWIN WILLIAMS.
<lb/>Published Monthly, in Numbers of 96 pages, $5 per Annum.</ab>
<lb/><p>THE DESIGN OF THIS WORK IS TO DEVEL-
<lb break="no"/>ope all the great resources of the country, as they are shown 
  in its Agriculture, Manufacture and Commerce. Essays and statements on
  these great interests will be given, with notices of Manufacturing Towns 
  and Villages, Internal Improvements, New Inventions, and Statistical Details,
  exhibiting the progress of American industry.</p>
<lb/><p>FROISSART’S CHRONICLES of England, France and Spain with an 
  Essay on the Character and Society of the Middle Ages. One vol. 
  4to. pp. 634. $3.</p>
<lb/><ab>SCARCE WORKS.
<lb/>THE BRITISH NAVAL CHRONICLE; a General and Biographical History of the Royal Navy, 20 vols. 8vo., bound, with numerous plates. Price $50.
<lb/>NILES’ WEEKLY REGISTER, (Subscriber’s Copy) in 30 vols, 8vo., bound. Price, $50.
<lb/>Subscriptions received to all the American and English Periodicals and orders for books promptly executed.
<lb/>FINDEN’S LANDSCAPE ILLUSTRATIONS, of the Prose and Poetical Words of Sir Walter Scott, with portraits of the principal female characters. The designs from Westall, Landseer, Leslie, Stanfield, Prout, &amp;c., with letter-press descriptions. 3 vols. Containing 120 plates; turkey morocco, extra. Price $12.
<lb/>FOR SALE, a single copy of "Sparking,” the last print of the American Art Union.
<lb/>LANDSCAPE ILLUSTRATIONS of the Bible, from original sketches by eminent artists.
<lb/>A few copies of the " Blind Fiddler,” from Wildie.
<lb/>J. SMITH HOMANS,
<lb/>Sun Office, corner of Fulton and Nassau Streets.</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>VANDENHOFF’S ELOCUTION.</head>
<lb/><p>SECOND EDITION.—This valuable work is being introduced into a large number 
  of the best Schools in the City and Country.</p>
<lb/><p>It only needs to be generally known to become universally established.</p>
<lb/><p>Testimonials are received from every quarter.</p>
<lb/><ab>From Rev. R. F. Burnham, Rector of St- Paul's Church, Hoboken.</ab>
<lb/><quote type="block"><p>“ Having seen, with much pleasure, a second edition, by your house, of “ A Plain System of Elocution,” I beg leave to express to you my opinion of the high merit of that work.</p>
<lb/><p>Its title is in keeping with the plan pursued in the book; a rare fact in
  this age of making many books. In the work may be found what this ago needs—a
  System of Elocution, that presents to the learner something tangible; and that 
  combines meaning with beauty, and beauty with force.</p>
<lb/><p>I hereby express the opinion that the Principals of Seminaries of Learning would 
  benefit the department of Elocution, by the introduction of Mr. Vandenhoff's System.”</p></quote>
<lb/><ab>C. SHEPARD, Publisher,
<lb/>191 Broadway, opposite John-street.</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>MANESCA’S ORAL SYSTEM OF TEACHING
<lb/>THE FRENCH LANGUAGE, </head><ab>pursued by his daughter, Madame Durand, either in class or
      private lessons, to Ladies and Gentlemen, at No. 35 Walker-street.</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>MUSIC FOR THE MILLION.</head>
<lb/><ab>Moore’s Irish Melodies—eight songs and five pieces, 25 cents. Six Songs and three Pieces from the Bohemian Girl,	25
<lb/>; Three Airs and two Polkas from the Bohemian Girl,	12£
<lb/>' Eleven of Lover’s celebrated Irish Songs,	25
<lb/>Nine Songs and Cotillions from the Ethiopian Serenaders, 25 Nine Favorite Polkas, by Strauss, Lubitzky, &amp;c„	25
<lb/>Gems of Scottish Song, containing fifty-seven Songs, Ballads, &amp;c.; in embossed binding,	(1 50
<lb/>Hunten’s celebrated Piano-Forte Instructions and Exercises.
<lb/>Same, abridged.
<lb/>Crivelli's celebrated Instructions and Exercises in Singing.
<lb/>Forty-three Sacred and Moral Songs, one vol.	$1 50
<lb/>The Founding of the Bell. By Henry Russell.
<lb/>Far Away in My Own Bright Laud. (Bohemian Girl.)
<lb/>Beauties of the Bohemian Girl. By Rimbault.
<lb/>Beauties of Torquato Tasss. By Donizetti.
<lb/>Beauties of L’ F.lisir d’Amore. By Rimbault.
<lb/>•• Long Time Ago." Variations by Czerny.
<lb/>The Loved One was not There. By Dempster.
<lb/>The May Queen.	By	do.
<lb/>A Home in the Heart.	By	do.
<lb/>Hear Me, Norma. Duett from La Norma.
<lb/>For sale by
<lb/>J. SMITH HOMANS,
<lb/>Boa Office, Foltoo-streat</ab></div>
<pb  n="416"/>
<lb/><div><head>TO THE EDITOR OF THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</head>
<lb/><p>SIR —WE WILL THANK YOU TO CAUTION
<lb/>the public against a set of imposters who are calling upon our customers, asserting 
  that they are engaged by us in the capacity of agents. In several instances they have
  succeeded in obtaining orders. But when the goods are delivered great dissatisfaction 
  has been given by the infamous and utterly base imitations. But still persisting that 
  the cards are our manufacture, they too often succeed in foisting them upon the 
  unsuspecting. We ourselves would strenuously caution the said parties that, should 
  they persist after this notice, we will try what effect a State Prison will have 
  upon them. </p><ab>We are, Sir, Your most obt’y,
<lb/>J. B. CAREY &amp; CO., Ornamental Show Card Manufacturers,
<lb/>34 Beekman-St. (late 323 Broadway.)</ab>
<lb/><p>An agent wanted for New-York City. Also one for New-York State —whose name
      will be published as our authorized agent.</p></div>
<lb/><div><head>GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE,</head>
<lb/><ab>THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE TEARS BY THE AMERICAN INSTITUTE FOR
  THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.
<lb/>GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY.
<lb/>No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.
<lb/>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
<lb break="no"/>tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young) in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
<lb/>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
<lb/>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M. daily for gentlemen, and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
<lb/>For sale “Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound. Price Five Dollars.</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>A CARD.</head>
<lb/><ab>WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANOFORTE,
<lb/>ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank-street, where his terms for giving
      instruction can be ascertained.	myl7</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>THE BOEHM FLUTE.
</head><lb/><p>PHILIP ERNST, Teacher of the Flute and Gui-
<lb break="no"/>tar, would inform the lovers of Music that he has now for sale 
      several of the above celebrated instruments, constructed in every respect
      in accordance with those now in use at the Paris and London Royal Academies.
      To be seen at PHILIP ERNST’S Music Saloon, 395 Broadway, near Walker-st.</p></div>
<lb/><div><head>THE BOEHM FLUTE.
<lb/>(NEW INVENTION.)</head>
<lb/><ab>Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music. London, the Conservatorie at Paris, 	
  and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.</ab>
<lb/> <p>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the ‘Boehm Flute,’
<lb/>110 FultoN-St. N.Y., anxious to introduce to the Amateurs of this city the
  above Important Invention, which has been so enthusiastically received and 
  generally used by the most distinguished European artists, feels happy in being
  able to place before them the following testimonial to its merits, signed by two
  of the most distinguished of our resident Artists.	</p>
<lb/><p>We hereby certify to the excellence of the Boehm Flute, as manufactured by 
  Mr. J. D. Larrabee: to the beauty of its tone, the perfection of its tune, 
  and the simplicity of its fingering, which renders a bril-liant execution 
  comparatively easy.</p>
<lb/><ab>Philip Ernst, (who has already introduced it successfully among his pupils.)			
<lb/>John A. Kyle, Principal Flute of the Philharmonic Society, and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm Flute, 41 Forsyth-st. New-York.
<lb/> Amateurs and Professors are requested to call at the manufactory, 110 Fulton-st.
      and judge for themselves.	</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>PIANO FORTES,</head>
<lb/><p>THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their nu-merous 
  friends and to the public, would, at the same time call atten- tion 
  to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished, 
  in elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.</p>
<lb/><p>The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department 
  of the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
  to the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
  upon examination, equal to any in the market.</p>
<lb/><ab>STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway. Manufactory, I3th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.</ab>
</div><lb/><div><head>PIANO FORTES.</head> <p>—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
<lb/>Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to
  the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establishment, 
  corner of Cottage-Place and Bleecker-street, which he will sell as prices
  unusually low.</p>
<lb/><p>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last
  twenty years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing 
  for two of the largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in 
  saving that his instru- ments will bear a favorable comparison with 
  those of the best makers in this country or Europe, and that they 
  contain all the real improvements of the day.</p>
<lb/><ab>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and Repaired.
<lb/>New-York, April 28d, 1845.</ab></div><cb/>
<lb/><div><head>JAMES PIRSSON,
<lb/>PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER,</head>
<lb/><ab>88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER-STREET, NEAR ELM.
<lb/>A Large Stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
<lb/>TERMS MODERATE.
  <lb/>FOR SALE—A splendid harp, nearly new. To be sold at a great bargaia for cash.</ab></div>
      <div><lb/><head>PIANO FORTES.</head><ab>—A. H. GALE &amp; CO.’s Ware-
<lb break="no"/>Rooms, No. 289 Broadway—Manufactory Third Avenue, corner of 13th street.</ab>
<lb/><p>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assortment of 
      Rosewood and Mahogany Piano Fortes, with from six to seven octaves, 
      embracing every variety of patterns, made in their well-known substantial
      manner, under their immediate and personal superintendence, by skillful and
      experienced mechanics, from the best seasoned materials. </p><p>These instruments 
      embrace many important improvements, which will recommend themselves, and 
      are finished in the highest state of perfection, with the best French grand
      action, warranted in every respect by the manufacturer.</p></div>
<lb/><div><head>PIANO FORTES.</head><ab>—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal-
<lb break="no"/>Street, N. Y.</ab>
<lb/><p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron Frames,
  &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice materials, 
  and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of 23 years 
  experience in the business.</p>
<lb/><ab>N. B. Wanted a second-hand Parlor Organ,
<lb/>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>F RILEY &amp; CO.,</head> <ab>No. 297 Broadway, (between
<lb/> Reade and Duane-Streets,) N. Y., Publishers of Music, and Manufacturers of
      Musical Instruments, wholesale and retail. In addition to their own catalogue
      (one of the largest in the United States,) they keep on hand the publications
      of all the principal Music houses. They are erecting a large Saloon in the rear
      of their store, where Piano Fortes of a superior quality, will constantly be
      kept on hand</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>PIANO FORTES.</head>
<lb/><p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway, 
      will keep a complete assortment of the largest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, 
      of the most superior quality ; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their 
      excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. 
      A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repared. 
      Piano Fortes always on hire.</p></div>
<lb/><div><head>BERTINI'S MENHOD FOR THE PIANO.</head>
<lb/><p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive work yet published
  in this country. Where pupils have used this method, the most rapid advancement
  has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is that
  the lessons, exercises, scales and studies are given in such PROGRES-sive order,
  that they enlist the interests of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly 
  through those mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often made irksome 
  in other instruction books. The time has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the
  Piano is of but little account, and it is only by the study of such methods as
  Bertini's that pupils will be enabled to read music with facility, and at the 
  same time become good musicians.</p>
<lb/><p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the rudiments of
  music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each lesson is fully 
  explained by marginal notes on the same page.</p>
<lb/><p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations from 
  professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of Bellini’s 
  Method over all others yet published in this country, most of them 
  having used the foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary
  to give a few of the names in the principal cities.</p> <ab>Boston.	New-York.
<lb/>Messrs. G. J. Webb,	Messrs. H. C. Timm,
<lb/>J. G. Maedar,	W. Alpers,
<lb/>H. T. Hach,	U. C. Hill,
<lb/>E. L. White,	F. H. Brown.
<lb/>David Paine,	Philadelphia.
<lb/>A. Kurek,	B. C. Cross,
<lb/>T. B. Moses.	Joseph Duggan.
<lb/>Albany—O. J. Shaw.
<lb/>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work. 
      American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Washington
      street, Boston.</ab></div>
<lb/><div><head>AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</head>
<lb/><ab>Redding &amp; Co..............................Boston, Mass.
<lb/>Colon &amp; Adriance....................Philadelphia, Pa.
<lb/>R. G. H. Huntington,................Hartford, Ct.
<lb/>George Jones,.......................Albany, N.Y.
<lb/>Thomas H Pease......................New-Haven, Ct.
<lb/>L. Willard,..........................Troy.
<lb/>J. R. W inser, Printer, 138 Fulton-street.</ab></div></ab></div>
</body>
<back>
      <!-- here is a sample place for contextual information: -->
      <div type="editorial">
        <listPerson>
          <person>
            <persName><!-- canonical name --></persName>
            <birth>
              <placeName><!-- where born; date on when= of <birth> --></placeName>
            </birth>
            <death>
              <placeName><!-- where died; date on when= of <death> --></placeName>
            </death>
          </person>
        </listPerson>
      </div>
    </back>
  </text>
</TEI>
